<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Running on Stupid Things</title>
    <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/categories/running/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Running on Stupid Things</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <atom:link href="http://mikedmorgan.github.io/categories/running/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>What a bunch of Kents</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I write this, the world has &lt;del&gt;gone through&lt;/del&gt; is in the throws of a global viral pandemic. How humanity
comes out the otherside is a matter of pure speculation. The only thing that I know, is that if this doesn&amp;rsquo;t
change how our society works, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog isn&amp;rsquo;t about SARS-CoV-2 (the virus responsible for the current state of affairs for future
readers). It&amp;rsquo;s about running, hills and adventures on whatever scale you can manage them. That&amp;rsquo;s what this
whole endeavour is about - to keep having fun adventures, no matter what.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, obviously, whilst the government mandated lockdown was in place we had to find more local adventures
that we could reach on foot or by bike. We had plenty of those, and discovered the delights of the South
Cambridgeshire countryside and it&amp;rsquo;s quaint villages. But there aren&amp;rsquo;t any hills&amp;hellip; For that particular fix
we had to wait until the government deemed that the viral pandemic was sufficiently under control that they
could relax restrictions on peoples movements and activities. This they did at the end of May, so Julie and
I took the opportunity (whilst the roads were still relatively quiet), to take a little drive down the M25
and finally complete a route that we planned originally for the beginning of the year, but was put on hold
because of, well, the obvious reason really. Anyway, we drove down to the lovely little hamlet of Titsey,
nestled at the foot of the North Downs that spans Surrey, Greater London and Kent. It was the latter 2
counties that we were going to tick this day; the highest point in both is around Westerham heights, just
off of the North Downs way. Unfortunately, the true summits are both inaccessible, one (Greater London,
245m)  lies just off of the busy A233. You could try to get there by foot - but you&amp;rsquo;d be taking your life
in your hands. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say we didn&amp;rsquo;t bother taking that risk. The highest point in Kent is Betsom&amp;rsquo;s Hill
(251m), which is in someone&amp;rsquo;s garden just the other side of the A233. So that ruled that one out as well.
Unperturbed, we scanned the map of the area and realized that the North Downs&amp;rsquo; way passes over the county
border, and pretty close to the same contour lines as Betsom&amp;rsquo;s hill and Westerham heights - winner, winner 2
hills for dinner!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some issues trying to find a suitable parking spot (Kent drivers belong in a special circle of hell),
and Google navigator trying to send us up a rutted farm track (Julie is convinced it&amp;rsquo;s just my terrible navigation, I&amp;rsquo;m convinced Google maps hates me), we parked next to the picturesque church in
Titsey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/titsey_sign.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Titsey church&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set off up a winding country lane that made it&amp;rsquo;s way steadily upwards; actually we ran across a field
first, but the farmer had blocked the path across it, so we turned around and ran up the road to get
around it. Farmers blocking public footpaths, grrrr. This detour knocked a bit of distance off our route, so
we added another little 1km detour down the hill towards Clacket lane, before running back up a bridleway and
resumed our intended route 50 yards further along the road from where we left off. Running through a very
pretty farmyard (very friendly locals), we started to head up hill properly through dappled woodland to reach
the North Downs way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/north_downs_sign.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;North Downs Way&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankful for the shelter from the blistering sun we trotted along the hard packed track, past massive houses
(not a bad place to be stuck in quarantine). Scooching up the side of one of these sprawling pads was a
footpath that wound around the perimeter fence and climbed up and up towards the ridge of the North Downs.
Unsurprisingly, this exposed our chronic lack of hill fitness (we live in the flattest region in England,
what should we expect?!). Up Betsom&amp;rsquo;s hill we plodded, determined to run at least some sections, we emerged
out of the trees along the side of a sheep field scattered with around 20-30 rugby balls. Either they must
&lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; like rugby, or they live next to a rugby field and have never kicked the ball back over the fence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We popped out next to Betsom&amp;rsquo;s farm and ran until it looked like the path sloped off in both directions from
where we stood. The GPS read 251m, bang on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/kent_summit_gp.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The summit&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/kent_summit_selfie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Summit selfie&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We snapped our selfie, splashed some tepid water down our parched throats and headed down the track to
merge with the North Downs way again. The rutted track soon turned into a metalled road, access for the huge
houses overlooking south-west Kent no doubt. For us at least it meant a bit of respite for our ankles, and
less effort as we headed gently down-hill for a mile to a cross-roads. Crossing over, we ducked down a small
flight of uneven steps, through woodland and ran parallel with the road. We materialised into a vast wild
flower meadow, full of small whites, heath browns and other meadow butterflies, and a stunning view across
Westerham and the Kent countryside. It made up for the lack of summit view for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/north_downs_view.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Downs view&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing through grassy meadows and coppiced woodland we eventually joined back up with the main road
that ran down to Titsey village. Our original plan had been to start the route from Botley Hill, then run
down through the grounds of Titsey place. So we continued along the North Down&amp;rsquo;s way, over the somewhat
treacherous path that used to run through shady trees, and was now exposed to the full sunshine. We tried
to avoid tripping over the detritus left over from this massive tree-felling effort, undulating over broken
ground and rising ever-so-slightly up hill to Botley Hill. Upon reaching the car park we soon realised
that the only way to get out of the grounds of Titsey place was via a 2-mile detour underneath the M25 or
back out through the car park. Balls. By our reckoning running back the way we had come and down the hill
into Titsey would still be about a mile, more than enough to have still covered the mandatory 10km. So,
off we trotted, back over the broken logs and twisted branches, thankfully this time we were going down
hill. As we passed the spot where we had previously joined, the road and path turned more steeply down-hill.
The path hugged the edge of a field, the boundary marked by an old rusty barbed wire fence, that in places
had collapsed and was lying in wait for any unsuspecting feet to catch-out. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve had to
concentrate so hard on where to place my feet before, as we dodged around fallen trunks, lengths of
barbed wire (neither of us much fancied a trip to the doctor to get a tetanus shot) and the odd rabbit hole.
Eventually the gauntlet came to end, unfortunately, so did the footpath! Thankfully, we knew that it was a
short distance down to the church so crossed the road to face the traffic and headed for the sanctuary of a
large grassy verge we could see about 300 meters down the road. The lack of traffic was certainly in our
favour and we made it to safety, finished the final few hundred meters to the church and our car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/Kent_Greater_London_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Route map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The run wasn&amp;rsquo;t ideal, it was definitely one of the hilliest we&amp;rsquo;d done (being out of practice didn&amp;rsquo;t help),
and we had to change the route a couple of times. Overall it was enjoyable though, infinitely more so by the
fact that we didn&amp;rsquo;t have to run up a busy A-road and risk our necks for the sake of some arbitrary goal.
We finished a lovely trip out with a packed lunch in the shade of the church yard, with a view down to
Limpsfield, in the shadow of the M25. I think our greatest relief was that we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to drive back
here and deal with the absolute bunch of Kents on the roads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/Kent_Greater_London_profile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Elevation profile&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A muddy eruption</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What do you do when you&amp;rsquo;re bored in January and live in Cambridge? Answer: drive for 2 hours to fulfill an idiotic
challenge to run up an arbitrary number of hills based on a somewhat tenuous definition of a &amp;lsquo;highest point&amp;rsquo;. It just
dawned on me that I can&amp;rsquo;t really justify this challenge, other than &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve started so I&amp;rsquo;ll finish&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s genuinely nice
that people regularly ask me how the challenge is progressing, but I also get a little bit of a sense of disappointment
when I tell them I&amp;rsquo;ve only run up &lt;sup&gt;16&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;103&lt;/sub&gt; hills. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is because people are constantly expected to be
wowed by some achievement or other - a sign of modern times that everything has to be better, faster, stronger, than
what came before. I&amp;rsquo;ve got great admiration for the people that step up to those challenges, but I&amp;rsquo;m not one of
them, and this is not one of those challenges. This is my challenge and I&amp;rsquo;ll do it however I want to. It gives
me (and Julie) a chance to see parts of the country that we might not choose to otherwise (some parts we &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt;
would never choose to: here&amp;rsquo;s looking at you Suffolk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to January. I&amp;rsquo;ve focused most of my efforts on running up the hills that are within a drive of Cambridge (a few
opportunistic exceptions, e.g. Brown Willy, Moel Famau, etc). The consequence is that we&amp;rsquo;re running out of hills to
visit without spending a whole weekend away. I&amp;rsquo;d estimate that we probably only have another 3-4 that we can
realistically reach in less than 2 hours of driving. After all, we don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend more time driving than we are
running; that would be disappointing. We figured that we could just about reach a decent starting location for the
highest point in Leicestershire (pronounced: liechestershestershire for any Non-British readers; honestly).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always knew that some of the county highest points would be a little disappointing - they can&amp;rsquo;t all start in a
quaint village or cosy pub. This one started in the car park of Coalville leisure center (glamour!). Bracing against
the cold, dull weather we set off on a paved trail past dog walkers and a little fishing lake, with a few brave souls
huddled up with their lines hanging limply in the water. The route we had planned looked suspiciously urban, but we
were pleasantly surprised to be running through fields (albeit parallel with a busy A-road). Up and over a disused
railway we crossed a couple roads and snaked through a housing estate, heading for our destination: Bardon Hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/leicester_sign_direction.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A sign&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a couple of miles we emerged onto the edge of a vast quarry, what remains of the side of the old volcano.
Gaining height proved tricky as the recent rain had turned the track into a slick, sticky quagmire. Up and up we
half ran - half crawled, trying not to slip over as the mud built up on our trainers, removing and last traction we
may have had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/leicester_muddy_hill2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Muddy hill&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually we emerged on to a wooded track, at least more sheltered, that traversed the side of the
quarry below us. Over a couple of stiles, we took a right fork at a junction and continued the slippery climb up and up.
Emerging on to a crest we passed a sign warning of the quarry blasting that took place regularly - thankfully it was a
few hours away so there was plenty of time to get up and back down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/leicester_quarry_dull.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Quarry&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/leicester_summit_distance.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A view of Bardon hill&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final slog up to the col that joined our hill with Bardon hill followed the Ivanhoe way. By this point I was
starting to get used to the mud (read: cocky) - so the universe taught me an important lesson and sent me stumbling
through the mud and plonked me flat on my bottom. All I can say is that I hope that the two dog walkers watching had a
good chuckle. Coated in iron-rich red mud we followed the path over a crest, through a stile and down to the radio
mast at we thought was the top. We could see on the map that there was supposed to be a trig point (also seen in
photos of Bardon hill). Following the winding tracks through a copse of trees towards, what we assumed, was the quarry
edge we finally emerged out onto a vista of Bardon Hill quarry and the urban delights of Coalville beyond. Replete with
an information board (who doesn&amp;rsquo;t love these?), the trig point (278m) stuck up proud on a promontory of volcanic rock, just
about the only evidence that we were stood on the summit of a 600 million-year old volcano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/leicester_trig.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Trig point&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/leicester_summit_selfie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Summit selfie&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/leicester_view_urban.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;What a view!&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cold weather stopped us from hanging around for too long (plus the potential threat of being blown up with
dynamite), so we headed back to the beacon and down a metaled track. This area seems to have been re-landscaped quite
a lot by, I guess, the quarry and land-owners, so some aspects of the footpaths and contours didn&amp;rsquo;t entirely match up.
Taking the best guess path we headed off on what we hoped would lead us round the base of Bardon Hill and back onto the
Ivanhoe way. Thankfully our noses for navigation have been well-honed by countless orienteering adventures (i.e.
getting lost), and we were on the right path through along a pleasantly wooded lane. The last few miles were largely
uneventful, following a narrow track along a school field, through another housing estate, eventually finishing through
the suburban sprawl before reaching the leisure center where we had started this adventure. Somewhat muddier than when
we set off, but full of the warm glow that comes with hill running, and a little bit of adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We dusted ourselves off, donned some warmer clothes and grabbed a cup of tea from the leisure center cafe before
enjoying the classic British past-time;a rainy car picnic, before commencing the drive back to Cambridge. Whilst this
was not the most exciting hill, it was by far not the least interesting (mud &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; makes it interesting), though I don&amp;rsquo;t
think we&amp;rsquo;ll be visiting this neck of the woods again any time soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/leicestershire_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;The route&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/leicestershire-profile.png&#34; alt=&#34;The profile - it even looks like a volcano&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun London</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time. That’s a terrible beginning for any story. But that’s the beginning of
this story. A story of sights, sounds, and gingers. Let’s begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A wise man said that only a ginger may call another ginger “ginger”. He also said
“cheese”, a lot, and had a penchant for lunging. This wise man’s name is Tim. Tim is an
entertainer from a strange country called Oz. We went to see Tim in his “show” before we
decided to run around our nation’s capital. It was funny. Very funny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This running challenge is about running to the highest point in each county. That means
that there is also a lowest point in all these hills. Our low point was London. Don’t get
me wrong, this wasn’t an emotional low point (that crown goes to Suffolk), but physically
the lowest county top is in London. As hinted to above, we went to see Tim Minchin the
night before our run, the plan was to then start at the end of Kensington Gardens and run
through (most) of the royal parks, then along the river, taking in the delights
(read: crowds) at Covent Garden before making the long arduous ascent to….22 meters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan started well - we dropped our bags near Blackfriars, but it turns out London had
a little surprise for us, in the guise of the lord mayor’s show. What is that I hear you
ask? Exactly. We’ve seen it and we aren’t any the wiser. Catching the central line to
Queensway we made our way to the edge of Kensington garden, trying not to make eye
contact with the local wildlife lest they think we were breakfast (REALLY BIG RATS;
gross).  We started, true to all form, by going in the wrong direction. Thankfully, an
overly-familiar Londoner tried to befriend us (I think he must have been new to London),
so we made our excuses and got back on course, running past the round pond and into Hyde
park along the Serpentine, making sure to spend a penny on the way. Duck! Ha ha ha, there
were ducks. And Herons. And seagulls, and stuff like that scattered in amongst the crowds
enjoying a lovely stroll in the park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/heron.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Heron&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, until two sweaty fools came barrelling through them, scaring pigeons left, right
and centre. We cut across the corner from the end of the
Serpentine to Rotten row, leaving the parks and heading across Wellington place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/wellington.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Wellington place&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out the other side we emerged next to Buckingham palace, giving Lizzy a wave, around Canada gate and into St James’ park. Dodging, pigeons and tourists; a blight on this earth, we ran
over the bridge and emerged on to the corner of Parliament square. This is where the fun
began. By fun, I mean semi-jogging passively aggressively behind oblivious tourists
running whenever a gap opened up. We joined the river Thames at Westminster bridge
passing the vacationers gawping at the fake façade covering Big Ben - yet still taking
photos! Strange people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/london_best_photo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Best photo ever&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking the clear path up the river, we ran past Embankment to Waterloo bridge, diverting
up to the theatre district by the Lyceum. We headed up Drury lane (no sign of the muffin
man though. The muffin man? Yes, the muffin man who lives on Drury lane).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/park_selfie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Park selfie&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We emerged on
to High Holborn road, almost the highest point, and trotted over to a derelict church with
a Greco front, next to the museum of comedy (ha!). We snapped our obligatory “summit”
selfie, and backtracked to the river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/comedy_selfie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Summit selfie&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that London had anticipated our run and had kindly closed all the roads
from Waterloo bridge all the way to Blackfriars bridge. How nice (nothing to do with the
“Lord Mayor’s show”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/gog_magog.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Gog and Magog&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Julie made me mention this “best” bit) Just as we were getting back to the station after
collecting our bags we encountered “brass band Bon Jovi” - a brass band playing Jon Bon
Jovi’s classic hit ‘Bad Medicine’. Certainly an experience I’ll never forget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all not a bad run - certainly better than expected given it was a Saturday
afternoon in London. Weather was a bit crap, but it was also in November, so can’t
complain. It was fun, we saw lots of different landmarks, including the Great Albert
Hall, Kensington Palace, Buckingham Palace, Big Ben, Houses of Parliament, Nelson’s
column, Covent Garden and St Paul’s cathedral. Call us tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NB&lt;/strong&gt;: My GPS device was miscalibrated so put our elevation at ~100 metres - this was
definitely not the case! The height of Holborn Hill is a dizzying 22metres, so here&amp;rsquo;s the
OS map we used with our route drawn out in faint pencil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/london_map.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Route map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warwickshire - A comedy of errors</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round12-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round12-md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This will be a short post, as I’ve heard that brevity is the soul of wit (Hamlet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a long time between Christmas and Easter this year. Too long. It got to the point where both Julie and I were getting run down, so we planned an impromptu break to the Cotswolds and Stratford upon Avon - Shakespeare country! We found a cute little cottage called the Old Dairy, complete with it’s own massive cheese press in the bedroom - thankfully it hadn’t been used for some while so the aroma of maturing cheddar did not linger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever we have a stay-cation there’s always the looming agenda of which county to visit, and whether we can run up the highest point.  We’ve done pretty well so far, and there was no reason to think Warwickshire would be any different. We originally planned to run up the county top for Gloucestershire as well, but sacked off the idea before we even left Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/warwickshire_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Route map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an afternoon wandering the streets of Stratford, encountering many a fool (and ice cream), we headed to our cottage in Cleeve Prior perched on the edge of the Cotswolds. We got ready on Saturday morning with a tasty bacon sandwich, packed up, and drove to the sandstone village of Mickleton. Already we had made our first error, by not planning a suitable parking spot, so we drove up the hill to Hidcote Gardens. Thankfully we had become officially “old” 2 weeks previous and brought a National Trust membership, win! Depressingly, our planned route would take us on a 7-mile circuit back to the car before we even reached the hill summit. We were going to have to literally run right past our car for another mile before we could get back to the comfort of clean clothes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/warwick_not_hill.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Not our hill&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/warwick_rape.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sunny fields of rape&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ran down, down, down, down, down, down, right to the bottom of the hill into Mickleton. Yay - what goes down must come up again. By this point of the day, around lunchtime, the sun was relentlessly beating down on us with little or no shade. ‘Shall I compare thee to a summer’s day?’ (Sonnet 18). Another error, we hadn’t thought to pack any sunscreen, it’s March! We set off along the Heart of England way, across fields of rape (the plant silly), then round the base of Meon Hill, complete with a fort on top (not that we could see it though). Sadly whatever remains were on the summit were inaccessible as it was on private land. Nevertheless we continued across farmer’s fields, full of the year’s first lambs frolicking in the sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/warwick_sheep.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fluffy sheep&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/warwick_field.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;No shade&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a very curious feature about the landscape in Warwickshire, which we could only speculate was the result of intense farming practises back in ye olden days. Long trenches and furloughs followed the gradient of the hill in lines across the fields. Of course, these rollers made for natural BMX-style jumps, so of course we obliged. A superman, a 360˚ - the latter was my next error. Running, jumping and rotating in the air is not my forte, and I almost certainly twisted something. Fool. On we plodded along the Monarch’s way, under the beating sun, with little chance of respite - Warwickshire is not a woody county it seems. As we approached Admington, my knee was causing too much pain so we took a little rest to stretch out and recover. Thankfully in my haste I had taken a wrong turning that led to a wee short cut, and stopped us having to run along the side of a fast country lane. Over the road we crossed, back onto the Monarch’s way for the final ascent back to Hidcote gardens, and the eventual final stretch to the summit. A curious large stone marker was placed at the base of hill - with ‘Ticket’ carved into it. Up the hill we climbed, at times steep, but always constant, on and on it continued for 2 kilometres (not vertically, obvs), through fields and copse, always with the company of lambs. Finally we arrived at the carpark - … miles into the run, only to turn away and up, up , up to the final summit. Climbing up a rutted farm track, still no ounce of shade. Finally we reached the final rise, past the trig point (sadly not the true summit), only to be confronted by an obnoxious cyclist pissing on the path - idiot. There was no great monument to mark the highest point in Warwickshire, just an innocuous corner of a ploughed field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/warwick_field2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fields&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/warwick_thinking.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Where are we?&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/warwick_stone.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Stone thing&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took a couple of photos, lamented the lack of any skulls for Shakespeare inspired poses, and made our way back to the car. Our reward? A clotted cream tea. Yum, and thoroughly well earned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/warwick_summit_selfie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Summit selfie&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/warwick_is_this_the_spot.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Summit?&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/warwickshire_profile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Profile&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An injury. Near-sun stroke. Running back to the car before even reaching the summit. Some might call it a comedy of errors, but it was all assuaged with one simple cream tea. We have seen better days (Timon of Athens).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. On a side note, we finally brought a tent, which means I get to trot out my favourite Shakespeare-camping mash-up. “Now is the winter of our discount tents” - ha ha ha. So funny.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rutland - Small but perfectly formed</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round11-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round11-md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Where the heck is Rutland? I hear you ask.  Well, according to some, it is the smallest county in
England, it holds the largest manmade lake (so basically half of it is a lake) and it is home to the
Nurdling World Championships (Nurdling = throwing pennies in a hole), the winners are crowned the
‘best tosser’, no joke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Route map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on these facts alone, this was shaping up to be a very exciting run.  In addition, it was
February (i.e. my birthday) AND spring had started early.  I think this may have been the only sunny
birthday I have ever had. Rather than trying to fit in all that Rutland had to offer during one hill
run we decided to go to this lovely county two weekends in a row (its only an hour from Cambridge!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weekend 1: A very windy (teehee) 23 mile birthday cycle around Rutland Water.  Mike will deny it but
he was clearly slipstreaming behind me most of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_bike1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland bday biking&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_bike2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland bday biking&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_bike3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland bday biking&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weekend 2: A sunny run to the top of the highest point: Cold Overton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that Rutland has lots of very pretty villages with quaint pubs and old churches, one of
which, Braunston, was the start point of the run.  Braunston is also the site of some historical
stone carvings which are located outside the Church.  If you are running through said churchyard (as
we stared off doing), don’t be too disheartened if you miss them.  If you like I can knock a few
chunks out of a rock, pretty much the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, to the run.  It was sooooo lovely, the daffodils were out and the sun was shining.  The route
took us past the church, and out into some open fields (luckily there was some cover for a nature
wee).  The track wound through Bushy Wood and Haycock Spinney often in directions we were a bit
surprised about based on the map, and out onto a wide farm track (excellent public footpath sign
posting Rutland - not even Mike could get lost).  We popped out onto a small road for a few hundred
meters which then lead onto a footpath where the ascent started up to a lovely viewpoint of the
rolling hills adjacent to a farm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_jump.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland jumping&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_view.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland views&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In classic Mike style we then ran down to the bottom of the hill, and back up a farm track, only to
find that we could just have continued straight on from the viewpoint to arrive in the exact same
place &amp;hellip; .nice one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few more lovely fields later and we had a great view of the highest point we were aiming for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_notHappy.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland happy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We crossed a road and found the track which lead straight up to our destination (yes, straight up).
The trees had recently been cleared and so we found ourselves dancing around trying to dodge roots,
sharp sticks of death and tripping stumps.  Finally the track joined a path across some farmland and
in a few hundred meters we saw the trig point in the middle of a field to the west.  VICTORY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/summit_selfie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland selfie&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_trig1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland trig Julie&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_trig2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland trig Mike&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After retracing our steps to the track we descended a short way before finding the footpath to the east which took us directly back to the village, the car, a pint and a charcuterie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We never thought that the February run would end sitting in a beer garden in the sun but hey, that’s Rutland for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_drink3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland drinks&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_drink2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland drinking&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suffolk-ing boring</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round10-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round10-md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After our high point of charging up Brown Willy (tee hee) on New Years day, we thought we&amp;rsquo;d keep the
momentum going with another county hill. One that I ashamedly had not completed yet, despite planning
the route when I first began this challenge: Suffolk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/suffolk_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Suffolk route&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So two weeks into the New Year we made the short drive from Cambridge to the little village of
Hawkedon. We knew from the outset that this probably wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to be the most exciting run, but we
literally had nothing better to do on this crisp Sunday morning in January. We parked up next to the
village pub (Hawkedon btw is very pretty), and headed out along the footpath, hugging the side of
the ploughed fields. The only other brave souls out that morning were a family with their scruffy
border terrier. A dog so friendly that he decided to join us on our run, until his somewhat
embarrassed owner managed to catch up with him, mud and wellies flying in every direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suffice to say that was were the memorable moments ended pretty much. We meandered across fields,
stumbled over stiles, and commented on the general lack of features and landmarks of any particular
interest. Sorry if you&amp;rsquo;re reading this and you&amp;rsquo;re from Suffolk, but damn, the countryside is boring
round there. We ran across a few more fields, and eventually emerged onto a wide farm track, where
a couple of hundred meters to our right was the highest point in Suffolk; not that we could see it
of course. The only discernable feature was a large radio mast surrounded by a small copice of trees.
We trotted up the lane past the radio antennae and came around the bend on a small country road. We
had hoped that there might be something to mark such an auspicious location - obviously we were going
to be disappointed. We wandered along the lane until we were roughly stood on top of where the highest
point appeared to be from our GPS location. Flat in one direction, flat in all directions. We took
some photos, hopeful that we had reached the dizzy altitude of 128m above sea level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/suffolk_top.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;What a view&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/suffolk_wee.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Summit selfie&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We retraced our steps for 500 meters and carried on down the wide concrete rutted farm track. After a
mile or so we came across a series of man-made lakes, spread out in a line across several tiers. These
had apparently been made by the land owner many years ago for his family to enjoy. Now it seemed they
were largely occupied by ducks and a couple of swans. We wound our way between the lakes, and along a
small track at the bottom that would eventually take us to what appeared to be an old (not Roman)
moat. Sadly the moat was no longer visible, nor the remains of the earthworks around it, but there is
a very nice house. Past this house we continued down over a small footbridge, making a horseshoe as
we tracked back southeast along the bottom of several fields, a babling brook on our left. Because I
can&amp;rsquo;t read a map properly, we prematurely ran up a small rise to the top of the field, only to realise
that we had not quite reached the end of the fields. Back down we went, and across a few more
boundaries, before we came across the blindingly obvious driveway that took us up onto the road. A
short hop down here, and across the final few fields we emerged down at the bottom of Hawkedon, which
had come alive in our absence (which means the pub was now full). After stretching out, we decided to
forgo the usual celebratory pint and head home for a nice hot cup of Yorkshire tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/suffolk_profile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Suffolk profile&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s done. I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to compile a list of county hills I would run up again, and the ones that
I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t. This is going straight to the top of the list, I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it as an exercise for the reader
to figure out which list I mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ta ta for now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A dirty brown willy</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round9-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round9-md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Insert standard excuses about writing a blog post months after the run]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julie and I have a very similar sense of humor, so I&amp;rsquo;m somewhat ashamed that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed
the county hill that would obviously be the most fun. Brown. Willy. &lt;em&gt;tee hee hee&lt;/em&gt;. This hill, by
far, was the most hotly anticipated for us. I think Julie spotted the name sometime in the
summer. A very quick Google of &lt;code&gt;Brown Willy&lt;/code&gt; (with the parental filters on), turned up a dream
come true - the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trurorunningclub.org.uk/trc-events/brown-willy-run/&#34;&gt;Brown Willy News Year day run!&lt;/a&gt; We figured that as we were
travelling half way across the country over Christmas, we may as well go the whole hog and finish
in Cornwall for New Year (also, this is one of the furthest points from Cambridge on the South
Coast). The race starts and finishes at the (in)famous Jamaica Inn on Bodmin Moor.  Little did we
know that this pub was famous, as it forms the setting for a book of the same name by Daphne du
Maurier. Numerous ghost stories had been reported by guests staying at the inn over the
centuries, some no doubt fueled by the dark corners and even darker rum they serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/jamaica_sign.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jamaica Inn&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a great location to see in the New Year! We booked a couple of nights, and over the course
of a week slowly made our way down to Cornwall, stopping with friends and family along the way to
enjoy the festive season (and train on a few hills).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Route map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The route was a pretty straightforward there and back again, with a little circuit up the side of
Brown Willy then off the back and around the base to pick up the same trail. As this was an
organised run it meant the navigation would (hopefully) be trivial. We&amp;rsquo;d heard that the moors
can be pretty grim at that time of year, and had been warned several times about the mud - more
mud more fun! The race start time was 11am on New Years day, so there was plenty of time to relax
after the nights celebrations (though we only just made it to midnight :/). The crowds started to
build from about half 9, then they swelled (I think  close to 500 runners turned up). Officially
this isn&amp;rsquo;t a race, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop the first back from being hotly contested. We&amp;rsquo;d had a
good few practice runs through the week, but this was unfamiliar terrain to us, and it looked
like there were some &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; serious runners in the crowd. Our goal was to get there and back in
one piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_begin.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Start line&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_start.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Starters orders&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the start point at the Jamaica Inn we followed the road round under the A30 and along a few
country lanes until we were diverted onto a rutted farm track. It was quite tight, with only 2
runners abreast which meant having to speed check and keep our wits about us in the slightly
cramped conditions. Soon enough, after about a mile or so the track opened up into the moor and
gave us a bit more space to settle into a more comfortable rhythm. Everyone was in high spirits,
and clearly enjoying the event atmosphere. This is something I&amp;rsquo;ve found from previous running
events, that everyone is in a really good mood and wants to be there. We&amp;rsquo;re all in the same boat,
embracing the suffering! The route headed up and over a few hills (Tolborough Tor and Catshole
Tor according to the map), when Brown Willy emerged across the boggy moor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_distant.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A glimpse of Brown Willy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of miles across the bogs, we carefully picked the right, and mostly wrong, paths to
avoid the worst of the deep mud. Thankfully Truro running club had laid out markers all along
the route to help guide us. They did an absolutely sterling job at organising the event, I doff
my cap to your skills. As we closed in on the base of Brown Willy the front runners started to
pass us. I don&amp;rsquo;t know who &amp;ldquo;won&amp;rdquo; in the end, but there was a bit of a gap between the &amp;ldquo;first&amp;rdquo; and
&amp;ldquo;second&amp;rdquo; place at that point. Perhaps even more impressive was the young teenager keeping up
with the adults in the top 10 or so runners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/cornwall_profile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Brown willy elevation&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my first proper fell race, and I&amp;rsquo;ve read and heard repeatedly that if you can&amp;rsquo;t see the
top of the hill then walk. Other than my lack of fitness on Moel Famau, this is the only other
county top so far where that was necessary. This part of the run formed another bottle neck as
runners slowly picked their way up the steep side of Brown Willy. I would have liked to move a
little bit faster, but caution is the greater part of valor, so it was better in the long run as
we were only at the half-way point by then. After trudging up the hill, for what felt like 10
minutes, we emerged onto the top, and the highest point in Cornwall!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_top.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Brown willy top&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top was crawling with elated runners, so we took a few photos, including the ubiquitous
summit snap (thanks random person), and enjoyed the view. The cold wind kept us from hanging
around for too long, it was January 1st after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_crowds.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Brown willy summit&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_stones.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Brown willt cairn&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the cold took hold we made the descent off the back of Brown Willy. I quite like this
part of hill running as you can let loose a little and just let gravity do most of the hard
work. However, the broken boggy rocky path had other ideas. We carefully picked our way down
the steep track, trying not to turn an ankle on the hidden rocks and rabbit holes. Elated with
having made it to the top of Cornwall we made our way around the base of the hill and re-joined
the route back to the Jamaica Inn. Back through the mud, back through the sticky bog. Although
this year was reputedly some of the driest conditions in the history of this run, it still
didn&amp;rsquo;t stop us from getting caked in peaty mud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/mid_mud.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Julie running in a bog&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mud continued until we got back to the farm track, by which point we had well and truly
settled into a comfortable pace, and were just enjoying the ride. There&amp;rsquo;s always a sting in the
tail, and this was no exception. The final rise up to the Jamaica Inn paled in comparison to
Brown Willy, but ensured that we had to really earn this county top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start and finish at a pub. Check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run at least 10km. Check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Summit photo. Check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Track route. Check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/muddy_shoes.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Muddy shoes&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this was the first time in quite a while that we&amp;rsquo;d hit all of the orignal requirements
for a county top. Nice one Cornwall. I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; enjoyed this hill, and so did Julie. Without the
pressure of navigating we could just settle into the run and really enjoy the scenery. I think
I&amp;rsquo;ll try to find some more county tops that have races in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A dirty brown willy</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/content/round9-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/content/round9-md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Insert standard excuses about writing a blog post months after the run]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julie and I have a very similar sense of humor, so I&amp;rsquo;m somewhat ashamed that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed
the county hill that would obviously be the most fun. Brown. Willy. &lt;em&gt;tee hee hee&lt;/em&gt;. This hill, by
far, was the most hotly anticipated for us. I think Julie spotted the name sometime in the
summer. A very quick Google of &lt;code&gt;Brown Willy&lt;/code&gt; (with the parental filters on), turned up a dream
come true - the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trurorunningclub.org.uk/trc-events/brown-willy-run/&#34;&gt;Brown Willy News Year day run!&lt;/a&gt; We figured that as we were
travelling half way across the country over Christmas, we may as well go the whole hog and finish
in Cornwall for New Year (also, this is one of the furthest points from Cambridge on the South
Coast). The race starts and finishes at the (in)famous Jamaica Inn on Bodmin Moor.  Little did we
know that this pub was famous, as it forms the setting for a book of the same name by Daphne du
Maurier. Numerous ghost stories had been reported by guests staying at the inn over the
centuries, some no doubt fueled by the dark corners and even darker rum they serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/jamaica_sign.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jamaica Inn&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a great location to see in the New Year! We booked a couple of nights, and over the course
of a week slowly made our way down to Cornwall, stopping with friends and family along the way to
enjoy the festive season (and train on a few hills).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Route map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The route was a pretty straightforward there and back again, with a little circuit up the side of
Brown Willy then off the back and around the base to pick up the same trail. As this was an
organised run it meant the navigation would (hopefully) be trivial. We&amp;rsquo;d heard that the moors
can be pretty grim at that time of year, and had been warned several times about the mud - more
mud more fun! The race start time was 11am on New Years day, so there was plenty of time to relax
after the nights celebrations (though we only just made it to midnight :/). The crowds started to
build from about half 9, then they swelled (I think  close to 500 runners turned up). Officially
this isn&amp;rsquo;t a race, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop the first back from being hotly contested. We&amp;rsquo;d had a
good few practice runs through the week, but this was unfamiliar terrain to us, and it looked
like there were some &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; serious runners in the crowd. Our goal was to get there and back in
one piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_begin.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Start line&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_start.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Starters orders&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the start point at the Jamaica Inn we followed the road round under the A30 and along a few
country lanes until we were diverted onto a rutted farm track. It was quite tight, with only 2
runners abreast which meant having to speed check and keep our wits about us in the slightly
cramped conditions. Soon enough, after about a mile or so the track opened up into the moor and
gave us a bit more space to settle into a more comfortable rhythm. Everyone was in high spirits,
and clearly enjoying the event atmosphere. This is something I&amp;rsquo;ve found from previous running
events, that everyone is in a really good mood and wants to be there. We&amp;rsquo;re all in the same boat,
embracing the suffering! The route headed up and over a few hills (Tolborough Tor and Catshole
Tor according to the map), when Brown Willy emerged across the boggy moor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_distant.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A glimpse of Brown Willy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of miles across the bogs, we carefully picked the right, and mostly wrong, paths to
avoid the worst of the deep mud. Thankfully Truro running club had laid out markers all along
the route to help guide us. They did an absolutely sterling job at organising the event, I doff
my cap to your skills. As we closed in on the base of Brown Willy the front runners started to
pass us. I don&amp;rsquo;t know who &amp;ldquo;won&amp;rdquo; in the end, but there was a bit of a gap between the &amp;ldquo;first&amp;rdquo; and
&amp;ldquo;second&amp;rdquo; place at that point. Perhaps even more impressive was the young teenager keeping up
with the adults in the top 10 or so runners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/cornwall_profile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Brown willy elevation&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my first proper fell race, and I&amp;rsquo;ve read and heard repeatedly that if you can&amp;rsquo;t see the
top of the hill then walk. Other than my lack of fitness on Moel Famau, this is the only other
county top so far where that was necessary. This part of the run formed another bottle neck as
runners slowly picked their way up the steep side of Brown Willy. I would have liked to move a
little bit faster, but caution is the greater part of valor, so it was better in the long run as
we were only at the half-way point by then. After trudging up the hill, for what felt like 10
minutes, we emerged onto the top, and the highest point in Cornwall!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_top.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Brown willy top&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top was crawling with elated runners, so we took a few photos, including the ubiquitous
summit snap (thanks random person), and enjoyed the view. The cold wind kept us from hanging
around for too long, it was January 1st after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_crowds.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Brown willy summit&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_stones.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Brown willt cairn&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the cold took hold we made the descent off the back of Brown Willy. I quite like this
part of hill running as you can let loose a little and just let gravity do most of the hard
work. However, the broken boggy rocky path had other ideas. We carefully picked our way down
the steep track, trying not to turn an ankle on the hidden rocks and rabbit holes. Elated with
having made it to the top of Cornwall we made our way around the base of the hill and re-joined
the route back to the Jamaica Inn. Back through the mud, back through the sticky bog. Although
this year was reputedly some of the driest conditions in the history of this run, it still
didn&amp;rsquo;t stop us from getting caked in peaty mud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/mid_mud.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Julie running in a bog&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mud continued until we got back to the farm track, by which point we had well and truly
settled into a comfortable pace, and were just enjoying the ride. There&amp;rsquo;s always a sting in the
tail, and this was no exception. The final rise up to the Jamaica Inn paled in comparison to
Brown Willy, but ensured that we had to really earn this county top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start and finish at a pub. Check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run at least 10km. Check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Summit photo. Check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Track route. Check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/muddy_shoes.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Muddy shoes&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this was the first time in quite a while that we&amp;rsquo;d hit all of the orignal requirements
for a county top. Nice one Cornwall. I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; enjoyed this hill, and so did Julie. Without the
pressure of navigating we could just settle into the run and really enjoy the scenery. I think
I&amp;rsquo;ll try to find some more county tops that have races in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A dirty brown willy</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round9-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round9-md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Insert standard excuses about writing a blog post months after the run]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julie and I have a very similar sense of humor, so I&amp;rsquo;m somewhat ashamed that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed
the county hill that would obviously be the most fun. Brown. Willy. &lt;em&gt;tee hee hee&lt;/em&gt;. This hill, by
far, was the most hotly anticipated for us. I think Julie spotted the name sometime in the
summer. A very quick Google of &lt;code&gt;Brown Willy&lt;/code&gt; (with the parental filters on), turned up a dream
come true - the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trurorunningclub.org.uk/trc-events/brown-willy-run/&#34;&gt;Brown Willy News Year day run!&lt;/a&gt; We figured that as we were
travelling half way across the country over Christmas, we may as well go the whole hog and finish
in Cornwall for New Year (also, this is one of the furthest points from Cambridge on the South
Coast). The race starts and finishes at the (in)famous Jamaica Inn on Bodmin Moor.  Little did we
know that this pub was famous, as it forms the setting for a book of the same name by Daphne du
Maurier. Numerous ghost stories had been reported by guests staying at the inn over the
centuries, some no doubt fueled by the dark corners and even darker rum they serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/jamaica_sign.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jamaica Inn&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a great location to see in the New Year! We booked a couple of nights, and over the course
of a week slowly made our way down to Cornwall, stopping with friends and family along the way to
enjoy the festive season (and train on a few hills).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Route map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The route was a pretty straightforward there and back again, with a little circuit up the side of
Brown Willy then off the back and around the base to pick up the same trail. As this was an
organised run it meant the navigation would (hopefully) be trivial. We&amp;rsquo;d heard that the moors
can be pretty grim at that time of year, and had been warned several times about the mud - more
mud more fun! The race start time was 11am on New Years day, so there was plenty of time to relax
after the nights celebrations (though we only just made it to midnight :/). The crowds started to
build from about half 9, then they swelled (I think  close to 500 runners turned up). Officially
this isn&amp;rsquo;t a race, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop the first back from being hotly contested. We&amp;rsquo;d had a
good few practice runs through the week, but this was unfamiliar terrain to us, and it looked
like there were some &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; serious runners in the crowd. Our goal was to get there and back in
one piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_begin.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Start line&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_start.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Starters orders&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the start point at the Jamaica Inn we followed the road round under the A30 and along a few
country lanes until we were diverted onto a rutted farm track. It was quite tight, with only 2
runners abreast which meant having to speed check and keep our wits about us in the slightly
cramped conditions. Soon enough, after about a mile or so the track opened up into the moor and
gave us a bit more space to settle into a more comfortable rhythm. Everyone was in high spirits,
and clearly enjoying the event atmosphere. This is something I&amp;rsquo;ve found from previous running
events, that everyone is in a really good mood and wants to be there. We&amp;rsquo;re all in the same boat,
embracing the suffering! The route headed up and over a few hills (Tolborough Tor and Catshole
Tor according to the map), when Brown Willy emerged across the boggy moor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_distant.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A glimpse of Brown Willy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of miles across the bogs, we carefully picked the right, and mostly wrong, paths to
avoid the worst of the deep mud. Thankfully Truro running club had laid out markers all along
the route to help guide us. They did an absolutely sterling job at organising the event, I doff
my cap to your skills. As we closed in on the base of Brown Willy the front runners started to
pass us. I don&amp;rsquo;t know who &amp;ldquo;won&amp;rdquo; in the end, but there was a bit of a gap between the &amp;ldquo;first&amp;rdquo; and
&amp;ldquo;second&amp;rdquo; place at that point. Perhaps even more impressive was the young teenager keeping up
with the adults in the top 10 or so runners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/cornwall_profile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Brown willy elevation&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my first proper fell race, and I&amp;rsquo;ve read and heard repeatedly that if you can&amp;rsquo;t see the
top of the hill then walk. Other than my lack of fitness on Moel Famau, this is the only other
county top so far where that was necessary. This part of the run formed another bottle neck as
runners slowly picked their way up the steep side of Brown Willy. I would have liked to move a
little bit faster, but caution is the greater part of valor, so it was better in the long run as
we were only at the half-way point by then. After trudging up the hill, for what felt like 10
minutes, we emerged onto the top, and the highest point in Cornwall!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_top.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Brown willy top&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top was crawling with elated runners, so we took a few photos, including the ubiquitous
summit snap (thanks random person), and enjoyed the view. The cold wind kept us from hanging
around for too long, it was January 1st after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_crowds.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Brown willy summit&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/brown_willy_stones.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Brown willt cairn&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the cold took hold we made the descent off the back of Brown Willy. I quite like this
part of hill running as you can let loose a little and just let gravity do most of the hard
work. However, the broken boggy rocky path had other ideas. We carefully picked our way down
the steep track, trying not to turn an ankle on the hidden rocks and rabbit holes. Elated with
having made it to the top of Cornwall we made our way around the base of the hill and re-joined
the route back to the Jamaica Inn. Back through the mud, back through the sticky bog. Although
this year was reputedly some of the driest conditions in the history of this run, it still
didn&amp;rsquo;t stop us from getting caked in peaty mud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/mid_mud.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Julie running in a bog&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mud continued until we got back to the farm track, by which point we had well and truly
settled into a comfortable pace, and were just enjoying the ride. There&amp;rsquo;s always a sting in the
tail, and this was no exception. The final rise up to the Jamaica Inn paled in comparison to
Brown Willy, but ensured that we had to really earn this county top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start and finish at a pub. Check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run at least 10km. Check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Summit photo. Check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Track route. Check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/muddy_shoes.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Muddy shoes&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this was the first time in quite a while that we&amp;rsquo;d hit all of the orignal requirements
for a county top. Nice one Cornwall. I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; enjoyed this hill, and so did Julie. Without the
pressure of navigating we could just settle into the run and really enjoy the scenery. I think
I&amp;rsquo;ll try to find some more county tops that have races in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BoGoF</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round8-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round8-md/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m getting too predictable. As I mentioned in my last blog post I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a rather
annoying habit of writing these posts several months after the event. This has the rather
irritating effect that I can only remember half of the details. Nevertheless, here goes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-one-get-one-free&#34;&gt;Buy One Get One Free&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clock is ticking.  It&amp;rsquo;s December 13th and I&amp;rsquo;ve only run 3 county hills all year. I said to
myself at the beginning of the year that I would do &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt; 5, preferably more. Not less.
Scouring my list of hills I noticed that the grid co-ordinates for two counties were
suspiciously close together. The two offending counties were Hertfordshire and Buckinghamshire.
Not only were there 2 neighboring counties with separate hills close to each other, but it was
feasible to drive there and back from Cambridge in a day, even with the ever present grind of
the A14 traffic works (note to self: this reference is going to seem &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; old when I finally
finish this challenge).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/hertfordshire_buckinghamshire_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;bogof map route&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We (Julie and I) planned the route to take in both high points, and try to avoid as many of
the roads that criss-cross the Hertfordshire/Buckinghamshire border. So we jumped in the car and
made our way down the M11 and around the M25 until we finally reached our destination at
Wendover woods. Conveniently the highest point in Buckinghamshire (and the Chilterns), was
located about 100 meters from the car park. Not to do ourselves out of a half decent ascent
however we turn away from the high point and ran down hill to get to the Hertfordshire high
point first. We trotted through the woods, encountering a surprising number of other trail
runners. I can understand why it&amp;rsquo;s a popular spot. There are a couple of hills through the woods
and it&amp;rsquo;s reasonably far from the busy roads, so numerous cross-country routes can be
concocted depending on your distance. If I had Wendover woods on my doorstep I&amp;rsquo;d definitely get
out running a lot more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/hertfordshire_buckinghamshire-profile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Elevation profile&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(FYI: I think my GPS needs re-calibrating as I just realised that it&amp;rsquo;s out by about 100 meters!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The air was surprisingly warm for a mid December morning. After about a mile we started
descending, keeping an eye out for the many roots and stones just peeking out the top of the
forest floor detritus, waiting to trip the unwary runner. Approaching the A41, basking in the
unusually warm winter sun, we turned a right angle to view our first hill in front of us. About
a mile across farm land was a wooded hill that formed a long ridge line spanning the county
borders. As the base of the hill began to steepen so the mud got stickier. And stickier. I was
determined that I should be able to run up this hill, bottom top, however the previous days rain
presented an unexpected challenge. You know those dreams where you&amp;rsquo;re running but not making
any progress? That. That is exactly what it was like. Every other step slide backwards, it was
less trail running and more mud-skating, but uphill. Even running by the edges of the path
provided little relief as it was overgrown with brambles reaching out their spiking arms to
snag on our clothing. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly the challenge I was expecting! Nevertheless, after
nearly losing a shoe (Julie), we rounded the bend in the path to find&amp;hellip;not the top of the hill.
Another 150 meters or so further on the hill plateaued out and we came to a stile next to a
wooden sign post and lay by. Checking the map it looked like the true high point was somewhere up the road, but no more than 50-100 meters. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t an obvious hump in the road so I jogged
around for a few minutes with my GPS device trying to find the 244m altitude marker, but no
luck. We must have run over it 2 or 3 times at least, so we reasoned the obvious spot for our
&amp;ldquo;summit selfie&amp;rdquo; was the wooden sign post. Oh what a heady summit, thanks for nothing
Hertfordshire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/hertfordshire_selfie1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hertfordshire &amp;quot;summit&amp;quot;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We carried on our merry way jogging through the trees along the ridge line of the hill. Coming
to a cross-roads we hopped across the tarmac road, following another runner, and continued
oblivious to the mistake we&amp;rsquo;d just made. These runs are never complete without at least one
navigational error. What I had failed to realise was that 30 meters to our left at the road
was the actual path we wanted. Upon reaching the other road at the end of the path did our
mistake become clear. Thankfully it was pretty minor, and we just had to suffer the ignominy of
running an extra half-mile along the road. At the side of a house we turned up the path, and
immediately started ascending through the forest on our final approach to the top. This long
and winding path, shared with a mountain biker (who may have been lost?!), followed the contour
of the hill around onto a large open forest track. Signs of families and walkers started to
appear,  indicating we were edging closer to the car park and our second hill. We eventually
emerged into a clearing with the last push up a gravel track to add a final sting in the tail.
Our next job was to find the Buckinghamshire summit, which we hoped would at least be better
marked than the previous one. A sign post to the &amp;ldquo;Chilterns Viewpoint&amp;rdquo; raised our hopes that
we would indeed find our target. A few minutes of wandering around in the woodland and we
eventually stumbled across this heady &amp;ldquo;view&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; &lt;/sarcasm&gt;; at least the summit was marked. We
took some selfies (it&amp;rsquo;s in the rules damnit), and walked back to the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/buckinghamshire_selfie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Top of the Chilterns&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all not a bad run, even if the hills were somewhat underwhelming.  There was no pub, but
there was at least a cafe to get a sausage roll and a cup of tea. I&amp;rsquo;d hit my target of 5 hills
for the year, just. There was also an alterior motive for running these 2 hills in December,
which I&amp;rsquo;ll leave until next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BoGoF</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/content/round8-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/content/round8-md/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m getting too predictable. As I mentioned in my last blog post I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a rather
annoying habit of writing these posts several months after the event. This has the rather
irritating effect that I can only remember half of the details. Nevertheless, here goes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-one-get-one-free&#34;&gt;Buy One Get One Free&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clock is ticking.  It&amp;rsquo;s December 13th and I&amp;rsquo;ve only run 3 county hills all year. I said to
myself at the beginning of the year that I would do &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt; 5, preferably more. Not less.
Scouring my list of hills I noticed that the grid co-ordinates for two counties were
suspiciously close together. The two offending counties were Hertfordshire and Buckinghamshire.
Not only were there 2 neighboring counties with separate hills close to each other, but it was
feasible to drive there and back from Cambridge in a day, even with the ever present grind of
the A14 traffic works (note to self: this reference is going to seem &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; old when I finally
finish this challenge).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/hertfordshire_buckinghamshire_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;bogof map route&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We (Julie and I) planned the route to take in both high points, and try to avoid as many of
the roads that criss-cross the Hertfordshire/Buckinghamshire border. So we jumped in the car and
made our way down the M11 and around the M25 until we finally reached our destination at
Wendover woods. Conveniently the highest point in Buckinghamshire (and the Chilterns), was
located about 100 meters from the car park. Not to do ourselves out of a half decent ascent
however we turn away from the high point and ran down hill to get to the Hertfordshire high
point first. We trotted through the woods, encountering a surprising number of other trail
runners. I can understand why it&amp;rsquo;s a popular spot. There are a couple of hills through the woods
and it&amp;rsquo;s reasonably far from the busy roads, so numerous cross-country routes can be
concocted depending on your distance. If I had Wendover woods on my doorstep I&amp;rsquo;d definitely get
out running a lot more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/hertfordshire_buckinghamshire-profile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Elevation profile&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(FYI: I think my GPS needs re-calibrating as I just realised that it&amp;rsquo;s out by about 100 meters!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The air was surprisingly warm for a mid December morning. After about a mile we started
descending, keeping an eye out for the many roots and stones just peeking out the top of the
forest floor detritus, waiting to trip the unwary runner. Approaching the A41, basking in the
unusually warm winter sun, we turned a right angle to view our first hill in front of us. About
a mile across farm land was a wooded hill that formed a long ridge line spanning the county
borders. As the base of the hill began to steepen so the mud got stickier. And stickier. I was
determined that I should be able to run up this hill, bottom top, however the previous days rain
presented an unexpected challenge. You know those dreams where you&amp;rsquo;re running but not making
any progress? That. That is exactly what it was like. Every other step slide backwards, it was
less trail running and more mud-skating, but uphill. Even running by the edges of the path
provided little relief as it was overgrown with brambles reaching out their spiking arms to
snag on our clothing. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly the challenge I was expecting! Nevertheless, after
nearly losing a shoe (Julie), we rounded the bend in the path to find&amp;hellip;not the top of the hill.
Another 150 meters or so further on the hill plateaued out and we came to a stile next to a
wooden sign post and lay by. Checking the map it looked like the true high point was somewhere up the road, but no more than 50-100 meters. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t an obvious hump in the road so I jogged
around for a few minutes with my GPS device trying to find the 244m altitude marker, but no
luck. We must have run over it 2 or 3 times at least, so we reasoned the obvious spot for our
&amp;ldquo;summit selfie&amp;rdquo; was the wooden sign post. Oh what a heady summit, thanks for nothing
Hertfordshire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/hertfordshire_selfie1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hertfordshire &amp;quot;summit&amp;quot;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We carried on our merry way jogging through the trees along the ridge line of the hill. Coming
to a cross-roads we hopped across the tarmac road, following another runner, and continued
oblivious to the mistake we&amp;rsquo;d just made. These runs are never complete without at least one
navigational error. What I had failed to realise was that 30 meters to our left at the road
was the actual path we wanted. Upon reaching the other road at the end of the path did our
mistake become clear. Thankfully it was pretty minor, and we just had to suffer the ignominy of
running an extra half-mile along the road. At the side of a house we turned up the path, and
immediately started ascending through the forest on our final approach to the top. This long
and winding path, shared with a mountain biker (who may have been lost?!), followed the contour
of the hill around onto a large open forest track. Signs of families and walkers started to
appear,  indicating we were edging closer to the car park and our second hill. We eventually
emerged into a clearing with the last push up a gravel track to add a final sting in the tail.
Our next job was to find the Buckinghamshire summit, which we hoped would at least be better
marked than the previous one. A sign post to the &amp;ldquo;Chilterns Viewpoint&amp;rdquo; raised our hopes that
we would indeed find our target. A few minutes of wandering around in the woodland and we
eventually stumbled across this heady &amp;ldquo;view&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; &lt;/sarcasm&gt;; at least the summit was marked. We
took some selfies (it&amp;rsquo;s in the rules damnit), and walked back to the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/buckinghamshire_selfie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Top of the Chilterns&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all not a bad run, even if the hills were somewhat underwhelming.  There was no pub, but
there was at least a cafe to get a sausage roll and a cup of tea. I&amp;rsquo;d hit my target of 5 hills
for the year, just. There was also an alterior motive for running these 2 hills in December,
which I&amp;rsquo;ll leave until next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BoGoF</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round8-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round8-md/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m getting too predictable. As I mentioned in my last blog post I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a rather
annoying habit of writing these posts several months after the event. This has the rather
irritating effect that I can only remember half of the details. Nevertheless, here goes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-one-get-one-free&#34;&gt;Buy One Get One Free&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clock is ticking.  It&amp;rsquo;s December 13th and I&amp;rsquo;ve only run 3 county hills all year. I said to
myself at the beginning of the year that I would do &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt; 5, preferably more. Not less.
Scouring my list of hills I noticed that the grid co-ordinates for two counties were
suspiciously close together. The two offending counties were Hertfordshire and Buckinghamshire.
Not only were there 2 neighboring counties with separate hills close to each other, but it was
feasible to drive there and back from Cambridge in a day, even with the ever present grind of
the A14 traffic works (note to self: this reference is going to seem &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; old when I finally
finish this challenge).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/hertfordshire_buckinghamshire_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;bogof map route&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We (Julie and I) planned the route to take in both high points, and try to avoid as many of
the roads that criss-cross the Hertfordshire/Buckinghamshire border. So we jumped in the car and
made our way down the M11 and around the M25 until we finally reached our destination at
Wendover woods. Conveniently the highest point in Buckinghamshire (and the Chilterns), was
located about 100 meters from the car park. Not to do ourselves out of a half decent ascent
however we turn away from the high point and ran down hill to get to the Hertfordshire high
point first. We trotted through the woods, encountering a surprising number of other trail
runners. I can understand why it&amp;rsquo;s a popular spot. There are a couple of hills through the woods
and it&amp;rsquo;s reasonably far from the busy roads, so numerous cross-country routes can be
concocted depending on your distance. If I had Wendover woods on my doorstep I&amp;rsquo;d definitely get
out running a lot more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/hertfordshire_buckinghamshire-profile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Elevation profile&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(FYI: I think my GPS needs re-calibrating as I just realised that it&amp;rsquo;s out by about 100 meters!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The air was surprisingly warm for a mid December morning. After about a mile we started
descending, keeping an eye out for the many roots and stones just peeking out the top of the
forest floor detritus, waiting to trip the unwary runner. Approaching the A41, basking in the
unusually warm winter sun, we turned a right angle to view our first hill in front of us. About
a mile across farm land was a wooded hill that formed a long ridge line spanning the county
borders. As the base of the hill began to steepen so the mud got stickier. And stickier. I was
determined that I should be able to run up this hill, bottom top, however the previous days rain
presented an unexpected challenge. You know those dreams where you&amp;rsquo;re running but not making
any progress? That. That is exactly what it was like. Every other step slide backwards, it was
less trail running and more mud-skating, but uphill. Even running by the edges of the path
provided little relief as it was overgrown with brambles reaching out their spiking arms to
snag on our clothing. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly the challenge I was expecting! Nevertheless, after
nearly losing a shoe (Julie), we rounded the bend in the path to find&amp;hellip;not the top of the hill.
Another 150 meters or so further on the hill plateaued out and we came to a stile next to a
wooden sign post and lay by. Checking the map it looked like the true high point was somewhere up the road, but no more than 50-100 meters. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t an obvious hump in the road so I jogged
around for a few minutes with my GPS device trying to find the 244m altitude marker, but no
luck. We must have run over it 2 or 3 times at least, so we reasoned the obvious spot for our
&amp;ldquo;summit selfie&amp;rdquo; was the wooden sign post. Oh what a heady summit, thanks for nothing
Hertfordshire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/hertfordshire_selfie1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hertfordshire &amp;quot;summit&amp;quot;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We carried on our merry way jogging through the trees along the ridge line of the hill. Coming
to a cross-roads we hopped across the tarmac road, following another runner, and continued
oblivious to the mistake we&amp;rsquo;d just made. These runs are never complete without at least one
navigational error. What I had failed to realise was that 30 meters to our left at the road
was the actual path we wanted. Upon reaching the other road at the end of the path did our
mistake become clear. Thankfully it was pretty minor, and we just had to suffer the ignominy of
running an extra half-mile along the road. At the side of a house we turned up the path, and
immediately started ascending through the forest on our final approach to the top. This long
and winding path, shared with a mountain biker (who may have been lost?!), followed the contour
of the hill around onto a large open forest track. Signs of families and walkers started to
appear,  indicating we were edging closer to the car park and our second hill. We eventually
emerged into a clearing with the last push up a gravel track to add a final sting in the tail.
Our next job was to find the Buckinghamshire summit, which we hoped would at least be better
marked than the previous one. A sign post to the &amp;ldquo;Chilterns Viewpoint&amp;rdquo; raised our hopes that
we would indeed find our target. A few minutes of wandering around in the woodland and we
eventually stumbled across this heady &amp;ldquo;view&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; &lt;/sarcasm&gt;; at least the summit was marked. We
took some selfies (it&amp;rsquo;s in the rules damnit), and walked back to the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/buckinghamshire_selfie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Top of the Chilterns&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all not a bad run, even if the hills were somewhat underwhelming.  There was no pub, but
there was at least a cafe to get a sausage roll and a cup of tea. I&amp;rsquo;d hit my target of 5 hills
for the year, just. There was also an alterior motive for running these 2 hills in December,
which I&amp;rsquo;ll leave until next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wales 0 - 1 Mike</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It will come as no great surprise to my readers that I&amp;rsquo;ve run up another hill, and that I&amp;rsquo;m writing this blog post several months after
the event.  I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is just my enthusiasm for this challenge waning (I assumed it would ebb and flow like the tides anyway), or
that I&amp;rsquo;m just settling into a more realistic routine.  There are 103 county tops on my list, and including the run I&amp;rsquo;m about to describe, I&amp;rsquo;ve
only managed to run 8 of them so far.  That&amp;rsquo;s 5 last year, and just 3 so far this year, which is a little disappointing given we&amp;rsquo;re coming to
the end of the 11th month and I need to do at least 2 more hills before the end of the year.  Fear not, for I have a cunning plan, a plan so
cunning that it would make Mr S. Baldric&amp;rsquo;s chest swell with pride - I&amp;rsquo;m going to do 2 tops in a single run (spoiler alert).  That, along
with one other that I&amp;rsquo;ve planned in Suffolk will finally take me into double figures before New year; mission complete (something about
counting chickens comes to mind here :/).  Hopefully, that will also give me the kick up the bum I need to keep up the momentum for next year
(I&amp;rsquo;ve got a special one planned for New Year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the main event.  Julie and I, with one of Julie&amp;rsquo;s friends, Victoria, were heading to the tip of North Wales for a friend&amp;rsquo;s wedding back in
August.  Julie spent a large chunk of her childhood in the North Welsh town of Ruthin (Rhuthun), which sits just at the feet of, what turns out
to be, Flintshire&amp;rsquo;s tallest hill - Moel Famau.  It took some discussion, and a lot of googling, to figure this out as I didn&amp;rsquo;t have my trusty
spreadsheet to hand.  We were also stopping with one of Julie&amp;rsquo;s childhood friends, Lindsey, who still lives in the area and was kindly putting
us up for the night before we continued the long drive to the Llyn peninsula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately Julie&amp;rsquo;s senses kicked in for this run, or rather perhaps her childhood memories of climbing this hill, so I was without her
lovely company (she kindly dropped us off at the start and picked us up at the end though).  However, Victoria is a bit of a running fan.  As
she recently completed her first proper fell half marathon in Cumbria a month or so before, I (read: Julie) managed to cajole her in to joining
me for this run.  I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure she enjoyed it, I certainly did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set off from Cambridge that morning, and got to Loggerheads about 2pm.  This was going to be the first run that wasn&amp;rsquo;t circular, which was
handy because it meant that Julie could drive round to the car park next to Moel Famau and meet us at the end.  The start was reasonably flat on
a dirt track, but still weaved up and down a little, providing us with the ideal warm up after sitting in the car for several hours.  I really
wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how my fitness was doing - we&amp;rsquo;d come back from the alps 3 weeks previously, so hoped that I&amp;rsquo;d retained at least some of that hill
fitness, but you can never be sure when all you have to run up in Cambridge are the stairs.  We weaved around for a few miles, over the
reasonably flat paths and fields, following what turns out to be the border between Denbighshire and Flintshire (see the map linked below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/moel_famau_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Route map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a little anxious as we approached the foot of the ridge that I&amp;rsquo;d planned for us to take, partly because of my aforementioned fitness
concerns, and partly because this hill was nearly twice as high as the biggest hill I&amp;rsquo;d run up so far.  It felt like a huge leap, and one that I
might end up regretting.  The weather was perfect.  It was clear, with a few clouds, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t oppressively hot (unlike Cambridge which
turns into an oven in the summer).  We set off up the foot of the ridge, along a small overgrown track, after less than 100 meters it became
pretty clear that trying to run at even a slow pace was way beyond my capabilities.  I&amp;rsquo;ve heard the mantra in fell running that if you can&amp;rsquo;t
see the top, then you should conserve your energy and walk up, but still keep a decent pace going.  So we power walked up the steeper sections,
and where it flattened out or dipped down, we ran.  I was a little disappointed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the fitness to run all the way - I&amp;rsquo;m sure
with a lot more training it would be entirely feasible, but I think it would take a couple of months of hill running realistically get to that
stage.  Nevertheless I enjoyed the run to the top, and Victoria makes for a good pacer (I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure she could have run up the whole thing
without any problems).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moel Famau has an old ruined fort at the summit, so it was nice to feel like we were on a proper county top, and it even had a trig point, win!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/summit_selfie_moel_famau.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Moel Famau summit&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent a couple of minutes up the top, keeping a look out for Julie and Lindsey, but decided to start making our way down as we were only half way
through the route.  It turns out Julie and Lindsey had some communication issues, so we would&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for an hour on top for them.  We started
down the steep slope, skidding down the gravel paths, arms a-flailing.  I could get used to this part of hill running!  We continued winding around
the hill along the wide forestry paths, first down, then traversing along the side of the hill.  I had planned a bit more elevation on this route, just
in case I had to walk up the biggest part, which was lucky.  We got to an intersection, where the choice was to continue along the nice wide track, or
go up into the trees on a small grassy path.  There was no competition, so up we went, into the unknown.  I thought it cruel not to mention the impending
sting in the tail to Victoria - I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind if she came along for some of the other hills, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to put her off straight away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/moel_famau_profile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Elevation profile&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we rounded a bend, I check my GPS and saw that we were coming up to the last incline.  We had both settled into a good pace, so there was a shared
determination to meet this final challenge without balking.  We pushed on, both taking heavy breathes to keep our tired muscles filled with oxygen.  This
final rise, that seemed to so short on the map, just kept on going, round the bend, on and on.  Neither of us was willing to give in; psychologically
pushing each other onward.  Finally, after was seemed an age (it was probably on a few minutes), we reached a flattening, hands on thighs, gasping in the
warm Welsh air.  I was glad we&amp;rsquo;d pushed ourselves.  The burning in my thighs and lungs felt good - this was why I was doing this, exactly because it was a
challenge.  In a single route I&amp;rsquo;d pushed my limits, and I&amp;rsquo;d found where they lay.  There&amp;rsquo;s something enriching about trying and failing.  If you try and
you succeed, you don&amp;rsquo;t always know how much further you could have pushed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished the last few hundred meters, with the gate to the car park approaching, Victoria decided to initiate a sprint finish.  One thing that is worth
knowing about VP, is that is quite competitive, and will take &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; advantage she can.  I thought it would be fun to do a final sprint finish, but before
I could finish the count to three she dashed off, leaving me aghast at her unsporting behavior.  I wasn&amp;rsquo;t having any of that so quickly set off, my
thighs pumping up and down, trying to gain the precious few meters her cheating advantage had given her.  I&amp;rsquo;ll say it was close, but it probably wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;br /&gt;
She got to the finish first, triumphant at her win, at any cost, and utterly shameless about it.  Oh well, you win some, you lose some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We swigged down some water we&amp;rsquo;d left in the car and hung around, enjoying the view out over Ruthin, whilst we waited for Julie and Lindsey to return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/the_view.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The view&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the highest and hardest hill; and I came up wanting.  Whilst I&amp;rsquo;m not expecting to be able to actually run up Snowdon, being able to run up a 500m hill
should be within my abilities.  I don&amp;rsquo;t if it&amp;rsquo;s a lack of motivation, a lack of hills in Cambridge, or a lack of time, but I need to change something if I&amp;rsquo;m
going to complete this challenge before I hit 40.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julie and Lindsey finally returned from the top, and we drove back to Lindsey&amp;rsquo;s parents for a cracking BBQ by her dad.  It rained, but it&amp;rsquo;s Wales so it&amp;rsquo;s
pretty much expected.  We didn&amp;rsquo;t let that dampen our spirits, the warmth of Lindsey&amp;rsquo;s Dad&amp;rsquo;s hospitality made us feel at home.  It&amp;rsquo;s a lovely part of the
country, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to returning to Wales, at least 21 more times!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/the_hill.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The hill&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The eating and drinking continued long into the evening.  We got up ready
the next day for the final drive to George and Lucy&amp;rsquo;s wedding, where ate, drank and danced our souls out.  An absolutely cracking weekend of fine weather
(mostly), good company, and excellent hills.  I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The wedding&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wales 0 - 1 Mike</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/content/round7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/content/round7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It will come as no great surprise to my readers that I&amp;rsquo;ve run up another hill, and that I&amp;rsquo;m writing this blog post several months after
the event.  I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is just my enthusiasm for this challenge waning (I assumed it would ebb and flow like the tides anyway), or
that I&amp;rsquo;m just settling into a more realistic routine.  There are 103 county tops on my list, and including the run I&amp;rsquo;m about to describe, I&amp;rsquo;ve
only managed to run 8 of them so far.  That&amp;rsquo;s 5 last year, and just 3 so far this year, which is a little disappointing given we&amp;rsquo;re coming to
the end of the 11th month and I need to do at least 2 more hills before the end of the year.  Fear not, for I have a cunning plan, a plan so
cunning that it would make Mr S. Baldric&amp;rsquo;s chest swell with pride - I&amp;rsquo;m going to do 2 tops in a single run (spoiler alert).  That, along
with one other that I&amp;rsquo;ve planned in Suffolk will finally take me into double figures before New year; mission complete (something about
counting chickens comes to mind here :/).  Hopefully, that will also give me the kick up the bum I need to keep up the momentum for next year
(I&amp;rsquo;ve got a special one planned for New Year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the main event.  Julie and I, with one of Julie&amp;rsquo;s friends, Victoria, were heading to the tip of North Wales for a friend&amp;rsquo;s wedding back in
August.  Julie spent a large chunk of her childhood in the North Welsh town of Ruthin (Rhuthun), which sits just at the feet of, what turns out
to be, Flintshire&amp;rsquo;s tallest hill - Moel Famau.  It took some discussion, and a lot of googling, to figure this out as I didn&amp;rsquo;t have my trusty
spreadsheet to hand.  We were also stopping with one of Julie&amp;rsquo;s childhood friends, Lindsey, who still lives in the area and was kindly putting
us up for the night before we continued the long drive to the Llyn peninsula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately Julie&amp;rsquo;s senses kicked in for this run, or rather perhaps her childhood memories of climbing this hill, so I was without her
lovely company (she kindly dropped us off at the start and picked us up at the end though).  However, Victoria is a bit of a running fan.  As
she recently completed her first proper fell half marathon in Cumbria a month or so before, I (read: Julie) managed to cajole her in to joining
me for this run.  I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure she enjoyed it, I certainly did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set off from Cambridge that morning, and got to Loggerheads about 2pm.  This was going to be the first run that wasn&amp;rsquo;t circular, which was
handy because it meant that Julie could drive round to the car park next to Moel Famau and meet us at the end.  The start was reasonably flat on
a dirt track, but still weaved up and down a little, providing us with the ideal warm up after sitting in the car for several hours.  I really
wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how my fitness was doing - we&amp;rsquo;d come back from the alps 3 weeks previously, so hoped that I&amp;rsquo;d retained at least some of that hill
fitness, but you can never be sure when all you have to run up in Cambridge are the stairs.  We weaved around for a few miles, over the
reasonably flat paths and fields, following what turns out to be the border between Denbighshire and Flintshire (see the map linked below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/moel_famau_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Route map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a little anxious as we approached the foot of the ridge that I&amp;rsquo;d planned for us to take, partly because of my aforementioned fitness
concerns, and partly because this hill was nearly twice as high as the biggest hill I&amp;rsquo;d run up so far.  It felt like a huge leap, and one that I
might end up regretting.  The weather was perfect.  It was clear, with a few clouds, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t oppressively hot (unlike Cambridge which
turns into an oven in the summer).  We set off up the foot of the ridge, along a small overgrown track, after less than 100 meters it became
pretty clear that trying to run at even a slow pace was way beyond my capabilities.  I&amp;rsquo;ve heard the mantra in fell running that if you can&amp;rsquo;t
see the top, then you should conserve your energy and walk up, but still keep a decent pace going.  So we power walked up the steeper sections,
and where it flattened out or dipped down, we ran.  I was a little disappointed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the fitness to run all the way - I&amp;rsquo;m sure
with a lot more training it would be entirely feasible, but I think it would take a couple of months of hill running realistically get to that
stage.  Nevertheless I enjoyed the run to the top, and Victoria makes for a good pacer (I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure she could have run up the whole thing
without any problems).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moel Famau has an old ruined fort at the summit, so it was nice to feel like we were on a proper county top, and it even had a trig point, win!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/summit_selfie_moel_famau.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Moel Famau summit&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent a couple of minutes up the top, keeping a look out for Julie and Lindsey, but decided to start making our way down as we were only half way
through the route.  It turns out Julie and Lindsey had some communication issues, so we would&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for an hour on top for them.  We started
down the steep slope, skidding down the gravel paths, arms a-flailing.  I could get used to this part of hill running!  We continued winding around
the hill along the wide forestry paths, first down, then traversing along the side of the hill.  I had planned a bit more elevation on this route, just
in case I had to walk up the biggest part, which was lucky.  We got to an intersection, where the choice was to continue along the nice wide track, or
go up into the trees on a small grassy path.  There was no competition, so up we went, into the unknown.  I thought it cruel not to mention the impending
sting in the tail to Victoria - I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind if she came along for some of the other hills, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to put her off straight away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/moel_famau_profile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Elevation profile&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we rounded a bend, I check my GPS and saw that we were coming up to the last incline.  We had both settled into a good pace, so there was a shared
determination to meet this final challenge without balking.  We pushed on, both taking heavy breathes to keep our tired muscles filled with oxygen.  This
final rise, that seemed to so short on the map, just kept on going, round the bend, on and on.  Neither of us was willing to give in; psychologically
pushing each other onward.  Finally, after was seemed an age (it was probably on a few minutes), we reached a flattening, hands on thighs, gasping in the
warm Welsh air.  I was glad we&amp;rsquo;d pushed ourselves.  The burning in my thighs and lungs felt good - this was why I was doing this, exactly because it was a
challenge.  In a single route I&amp;rsquo;d pushed my limits, and I&amp;rsquo;d found where they lay.  There&amp;rsquo;s something enriching about trying and failing.  If you try and
you succeed, you don&amp;rsquo;t always know how much further you could have pushed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished the last few hundred meters, with the gate to the car park approaching, Victoria decided to initiate a sprint finish.  One thing that is worth
knowing about VP, is that is quite competitive, and will take &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; advantage she can.  I thought it would be fun to do a final sprint finish, but before
I could finish the count to three she dashed off, leaving me aghast at her unsporting behavior.  I wasn&amp;rsquo;t having any of that so quickly set off, my
thighs pumping up and down, trying to gain the precious few meters her cheating advantage had given her.  I&amp;rsquo;ll say it was close, but it probably wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;br /&gt;
She got to the finish first, triumphant at her win, at any cost, and utterly shameless about it.  Oh well, you win some, you lose some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We swigged down some water we&amp;rsquo;d left in the car and hung around, enjoying the view out over Ruthin, whilst we waited for Julie and Lindsey to return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/the_view.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The view&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the highest and hardest hill; and I came up wanting.  Whilst I&amp;rsquo;m not expecting to be able to actually run up Snowdon, being able to run up a 500m hill
should be within my abilities.  I don&amp;rsquo;t if it&amp;rsquo;s a lack of motivation, a lack of hills in Cambridge, or a lack of time, but I need to change something if I&amp;rsquo;m
going to complete this challenge before I hit 40.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julie and Lindsey finally returned from the top, and we drove back to Lindsey&amp;rsquo;s parents for a cracking BBQ by her dad.  It rained, but it&amp;rsquo;s Wales so it&amp;rsquo;s
pretty much expected.  We didn&amp;rsquo;t let that dampen our spirits, the warmth of Lindsey&amp;rsquo;s Dad&amp;rsquo;s hospitality made us feel at home.  It&amp;rsquo;s a lovely part of the
country, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to returning to Wales, at least 21 more times!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/the_hill.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The hill&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The eating and drinking continued long into the evening.  We got up ready
the next day for the final drive to George and Lucy&amp;rsquo;s wedding, where ate, drank and danced our souls out.  An absolutely cracking weekend of fine weather
(mostly), good company, and excellent hills.  I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The wedding&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wales 0 - 1 Mike</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It will come as no great surprise to my readers that I&amp;rsquo;ve run up another hill, and that I&amp;rsquo;m writing this blog post several months after
the event.  I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is just my enthusiasm for this challenge waning (I assumed it would ebb and flow like the tides anyway), or
that I&amp;rsquo;m just settling into a more realistic routine.  There are 103 county tops on my list, and including the run I&amp;rsquo;m about to describe, I&amp;rsquo;ve
only managed to run 8 of them so far.  That&amp;rsquo;s 5 last year, and just 3 so far this year, which is a little disappointing given we&amp;rsquo;re coming to
the end of the 11th month and I need to do at least 2 more hills before the end of the year.  Fear not, for I have a cunning plan, a plan so
cunning that it would make Mr S. Baldric&amp;rsquo;s chest swell with pride - I&amp;rsquo;m going to do 2 tops in a single run (spoiler alert).  That, along
with one other that I&amp;rsquo;ve planned in Suffolk will finally take me into double figures before New year; mission complete (something about
counting chickens comes to mind here :/).  Hopefully, that will also give me the kick up the bum I need to keep up the momentum for next year
(I&amp;rsquo;ve got a special one planned for New Year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the main event.  Julie and I, with one of Julie&amp;rsquo;s friends, Victoria, were heading to the tip of North Wales for a friend&amp;rsquo;s wedding back in
August.  Julie spent a large chunk of her childhood in the North Welsh town of Ruthin (Rhuthun), which sits just at the feet of, what turns out
to be, Flintshire&amp;rsquo;s tallest hill - Moel Famau.  It took some discussion, and a lot of googling, to figure this out as I didn&amp;rsquo;t have my trusty
spreadsheet to hand.  We were also stopping with one of Julie&amp;rsquo;s childhood friends, Lindsey, who still lives in the area and was kindly putting
us up for the night before we continued the long drive to the Llyn peninsula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately Julie&amp;rsquo;s senses kicked in for this run, or rather perhaps her childhood memories of climbing this hill, so I was without her
lovely company (she kindly dropped us off at the start and picked us up at the end though).  However, Victoria is a bit of a running fan.  As
she recently completed her first proper fell half marathon in Cumbria a month or so before, I (read: Julie) managed to cajole her in to joining
me for this run.  I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure she enjoyed it, I certainly did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set off from Cambridge that morning, and got to Loggerheads about 2pm.  This was going to be the first run that wasn&amp;rsquo;t circular, which was
handy because it meant that Julie could drive round to the car park next to Moel Famau and meet us at the end.  The start was reasonably flat on
a dirt track, but still weaved up and down a little, providing us with the ideal warm up after sitting in the car for several hours.  I really
wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how my fitness was doing - we&amp;rsquo;d come back from the alps 3 weeks previously, so hoped that I&amp;rsquo;d retained at least some of that hill
fitness, but you can never be sure when all you have to run up in Cambridge are the stairs.  We weaved around for a few miles, over the
reasonably flat paths and fields, following what turns out to be the border between Denbighshire and Flintshire (see the map linked below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/moel_famau_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Route map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a little anxious as we approached the foot of the ridge that I&amp;rsquo;d planned for us to take, partly because of my aforementioned fitness
concerns, and partly because this hill was nearly twice as high as the biggest hill I&amp;rsquo;d run up so far.  It felt like a huge leap, and one that I
might end up regretting.  The weather was perfect.  It was clear, with a few clouds, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t oppressively hot (unlike Cambridge which
turns into an oven in the summer).  We set off up the foot of the ridge, along a small overgrown track, after less than 100 meters it became
pretty clear that trying to run at even a slow pace was way beyond my capabilities.  I&amp;rsquo;ve heard the mantra in fell running that if you can&amp;rsquo;t
see the top, then you should conserve your energy and walk up, but still keep a decent pace going.  So we power walked up the steeper sections,
and where it flattened out or dipped down, we ran.  I was a little disappointed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the fitness to run all the way - I&amp;rsquo;m sure
with a lot more training it would be entirely feasible, but I think it would take a couple of months of hill running realistically get to that
stage.  Nevertheless I enjoyed the run to the top, and Victoria makes for a good pacer (I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure she could have run up the whole thing
without any problems).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moel Famau has an old ruined fort at the summit, so it was nice to feel like we were on a proper county top, and it even had a trig point, win!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/summit_selfie_moel_famau.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Moel Famau summit&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent a couple of minutes up the top, keeping a look out for Julie and Lindsey, but decided to start making our way down as we were only half way
through the route.  It turns out Julie and Lindsey had some communication issues, so we would&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for an hour on top for them.  We started
down the steep slope, skidding down the gravel paths, arms a-flailing.  I could get used to this part of hill running!  We continued winding around
the hill along the wide forestry paths, first down, then traversing along the side of the hill.  I had planned a bit more elevation on this route, just
in case I had to walk up the biggest part, which was lucky.  We got to an intersection, where the choice was to continue along the nice wide track, or
go up into the trees on a small grassy path.  There was no competition, so up we went, into the unknown.  I thought it cruel not to mention the impending
sting in the tail to Victoria - I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind if she came along for some of the other hills, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to put her off straight away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/moel_famau_profile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Elevation profile&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we rounded a bend, I check my GPS and saw that we were coming up to the last incline.  We had both settled into a good pace, so there was a shared
determination to meet this final challenge without balking.  We pushed on, both taking heavy breathes to keep our tired muscles filled with oxygen.  This
final rise, that seemed to so short on the map, just kept on going, round the bend, on and on.  Neither of us was willing to give in; psychologically
pushing each other onward.  Finally, after was seemed an age (it was probably on a few minutes), we reached a flattening, hands on thighs, gasping in the
warm Welsh air.  I was glad we&amp;rsquo;d pushed ourselves.  The burning in my thighs and lungs felt good - this was why I was doing this, exactly because it was a
challenge.  In a single route I&amp;rsquo;d pushed my limits, and I&amp;rsquo;d found where they lay.  There&amp;rsquo;s something enriching about trying and failing.  If you try and
you succeed, you don&amp;rsquo;t always know how much further you could have pushed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished the last few hundred meters, with the gate to the car park approaching, Victoria decided to initiate a sprint finish.  One thing that is worth
knowing about VP, is that is quite competitive, and will take &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; advantage she can.  I thought it would be fun to do a final sprint finish, but before
I could finish the count to three she dashed off, leaving me aghast at her unsporting behavior.  I wasn&amp;rsquo;t having any of that so quickly set off, my
thighs pumping up and down, trying to gain the precious few meters her cheating advantage had given her.  I&amp;rsquo;ll say it was close, but it probably wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;br /&gt;
She got to the finish first, triumphant at her win, at any cost, and utterly shameless about it.  Oh well, you win some, you lose some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We swigged down some water we&amp;rsquo;d left in the car and hung around, enjoying the view out over Ruthin, whilst we waited for Julie and Lindsey to return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/the_view.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The view&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the highest and hardest hill; and I came up wanting.  Whilst I&amp;rsquo;m not expecting to be able to actually run up Snowdon, being able to run up a 500m hill
should be within my abilities.  I don&amp;rsquo;t if it&amp;rsquo;s a lack of motivation, a lack of hills in Cambridge, or a lack of time, but I need to change something if I&amp;rsquo;m
going to complete this challenge before I hit 40.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julie and Lindsey finally returned from the top, and we drove back to Lindsey&amp;rsquo;s parents for a cracking BBQ by her dad.  It rained, but it&amp;rsquo;s Wales so it&amp;rsquo;s
pretty much expected.  We didn&amp;rsquo;t let that dampen our spirits, the warmth of Lindsey&amp;rsquo;s Dad&amp;rsquo;s hospitality made us feel at home.  It&amp;rsquo;s a lovely part of the
country, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to returning to Wales, at least 21 more times!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/the_hill.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The hill&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The eating and drinking continued long into the evening.  We got up ready
the next day for the final drive to George and Lucy&amp;rsquo;s wedding, where ate, drank and danced our souls out.  An absolutely cracking weekend of fine weather
(mostly), good company, and excellent hills.  I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The wedding&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>