<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Running on Stupid Things</title>
    <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/categories/running/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Running on Stupid Things</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <atom:link href="http://mikedmorgan.github.io/categories/running/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Wales 0 - 1 Mike</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It will come as no great surprise to my readers that I&amp;rsquo;ve run up another hill, and that I&amp;rsquo;m writing this blog post several months after
the event.  I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is just my enthusiasm for this challenge waning (I assumed it would ebb and flow like the tides anyway), or
that I&amp;rsquo;m just settling into a more realistic routine.  There are 103 county tops on my list, and including the run I&amp;rsquo;m about to describe, I&amp;rsquo;ve
only managed to run 8 of them so far.  That&amp;rsquo;s 5 last year, and just 3 so far this year, which is a little disappointing given we&amp;rsquo;re coming to
the end of the 11th month and I need to do at least 2 more hills before the end of the year.  Fear not, for I have a cunning plan, a plan so
cunning that it would make Mr S. Baldric&amp;rsquo;s chest swell with pride - I&amp;rsquo;m going to do 2 tops in a single run (spoiler alert).  That, along
with one other that I&amp;rsquo;ve planned in Suffolk will finally take me into double figures before New year; mission complete (something about
counting chickens comes to mind here :/).  Hopefully, that will also give me the kick up the bum I need to keep up the momentum for next year
(I&amp;rsquo;ve got a special one planned for New Year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the main event.  Julie and I, with one of Julie&amp;rsquo;s friends, Victoria, were heading to the tip of North Wales for a friend&amp;rsquo;s wedding back in
August.  Julie spent a large chunk of her childhood in the North Welsh town of Ruthin (Rhuthun), which sits just at the feet of, what turns out
to be, Flintshire&amp;rsquo;s tallest hill - Moel Famau.  It took some discussion, and a lot of googling, to figure this out as I didn&amp;rsquo;t have my trusty
spreadsheet to hand.  We were also stopping with one of Julie&amp;rsquo;s childhood friends, Lindsey, who still lives in the area and was kindly putting
us up for the night before we continued the long drive to the Llyn peninsula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately Julie&amp;rsquo;s senses kicked in for this run, or rather perhaps her childhood memories of climbing this hill, so I was without her
lovely company (she kindly dropped us off at the start and picked us up at the end though).  However, Victoria is a bit of a running fan.  As
she recently completed her first proper fell half marathon in Cumbria a month or so before, I (read: Julie) managed to cajole her in to joining
me for this run.  I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure she enjoyed it, I certainly did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set off from Cambridge that morning, and got to Loggerheads about 2pm.  This was going to be the first run that wasn&amp;rsquo;t circular, which was
handy because it meant that Julie could drive round to the car park next to Moel Famau and meet us at the end.  The start was reasonably flat on
a dirt track, but still weaved up and down a little, providing us with the ideal warm up after sitting in the car for several hours.  I really
wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how my fitness was doing - we&amp;rsquo;d come back from the alps 3 weeks previously, so hoped that I&amp;rsquo;d retained at least some of that hill
fitness, but you can never be sure when all you have to run up in Cambridge are the stairs.  We weaved around for a few miles, over the
reasonably flat paths and fields, following what turns out to be the border between Denbighshire and Flintshire (see the map linked below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/moel_famau_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Route map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a little anxious as we approached the foot of the ridge that I&amp;rsquo;d planned for us to take, partly because of my aforementioned fitness
concerns, and partly because this hill was nearly twice as high as the biggest hill I&amp;rsquo;d run up so far.  It felt like a huge leap, and one that I
might end up regretting.  The weather was perfect.  It was clear, with a few clouds, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t oppressively hot (unlike Cambridge which
turns into an oven in the summer).  We set off up the foot of the ridge, along a small overgrown track, after less than 100 meters it became
pretty clear that trying to run at even a slow pace was way beyond my capabilities.  I&amp;rsquo;ve heard the mantra in fell running that if you can&amp;rsquo;t
see the top, then you should conserve your energy and walk up, but still keep a decent pace going.  So we power walked up the steeper sections,
and where it flattened out or dipped down, we ran.  I was a little disappointed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the fitness to run all the way - I&amp;rsquo;m sure
with a lot more training it would be entirely feasible, but I think it would take a couple of months of hill running realistically get to that
stage.  Nevertheless I enjoyed the run to the top, and Victoria makes for a good pacer (I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure she could have run up the whole thing
without any problems).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moel Famau has an old ruined fort at the summit, so it was nice to feel like we were on a proper county top, and it even had a trig point, win!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/summit_selfie_moel_famau.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Moel Famau summit&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent a couple of minutes up the top, keeping a look out for Julie and Lindsey, but decided to start making our way down as we were only half way
through the route.  It turns out Julie and Lindsey had some communication issues, so we would&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for an hour on top for them.  We started
down the steep slope, skidding down the gravel paths, arms a-flailing.  I could get used to this part of hill running!  We continued winding around
the hill along the wide forestry paths, first down, then traversing along the side of the hill.  I had planned a bit more elevation on this route, just
in case I had to walk up the biggest part, which was lucky.  We got to an intersection, where the choice was to continue along the nice wide track, or
go up into the trees on a small grassy path.  There was no competition, so up we went, into the unknown.  I thought it cruel not to mention the impending
sting in the tail to Victoria - I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind if she came along for some of the other hills, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to put her off straight away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/moel_famau_profile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Elevation profile&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we rounded a bend, I check my GPS and saw that we were coming up to the last incline.  We had both settled into a good pace, so there was a shared
determination to meet this final challenge without balking.  We pushed on, both taking heavy breathes to keep our tired muscles filled with oxygen.  This
final rise, that seemed to so short on the map, just kept on going, round the bend, on and on.  Neither of us was willing to give in; psychologically
pushing each other onward.  Finally, after was seemed an age (it was probably on a few minutes), we reached a flattening, hands on thighs, gasping in the
warm Welsh air.  I was glad we&amp;rsquo;d pushed ourselves.  The burning in my thighs and lungs felt good - this was why I was doing this, exactly because it was a
challenge.  In a single route I&amp;rsquo;d pushed my limits, and I&amp;rsquo;d found where they lay.  There&amp;rsquo;s something enriching about trying and failing.  If you try and
you succeed, you don&amp;rsquo;t always know how much further you could have pushed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished the last few hundred meters, with the gate to the car park approaching, Victoria decided to initiate a sprint finish.  One thing that is worth
knowing about VP, is that is quite competitive, and will take &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; advantage she can.  I thought it would be fun to do a final sprint finish, but before
I could finish the count to three she dashed off, leaving me aghast at her unsporting behavior.  I wasn&amp;rsquo;t having any of that so quickly set off, my
thighs pumping up and down, trying to gain the precious few meters her cheating advantage had given her.  I&amp;rsquo;ll say it was close, but it probably wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;br /&gt;
She got to the finish first, triumphant at her win, at any cost, and utterly shameless about it.  Oh well, you win some, you lose some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We swigged down some water we&amp;rsquo;d left in the car and hung around, enjoying the view out over Ruthin, whilst we waited for Julie and Lindsey to return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/the_view.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The view&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the highest and hardest hill; and I came up wanting.  Whilst I&amp;rsquo;m not expecting to be able to actually run up Snowdon, being able to run up a 500m hill
should be within my abilities.  I don&amp;rsquo;t if it&amp;rsquo;s a lack of motivation, a lack of hills in Cambridge, or a lack of time, but I need to change something if I&amp;rsquo;m
going to complete this challenge before I hit 40.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julie and Lindsey finally returned from the top, and we drove back to Lindsey&amp;rsquo;s parents for a cracking BBQ by her dad.  It rained, but it&amp;rsquo;s Wales so it&amp;rsquo;s
pretty much expected.  We didn&amp;rsquo;t let that dampen our spirits, the warmth of Lindsey&amp;rsquo;s Dad&amp;rsquo;s hospitality made us feel at home.  It&amp;rsquo;s a lovely part of the
country, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to returning to Wales, at least 21 more times!  The eating and drinking continued long into the evening.  We got up ready
the next day for the final drive to George and Lucy&amp;rsquo;s wedding, where ate, drank and danced our souls out.  An absolutely cracking weekend of fine weather
(mostly), good company, and excellent hills.  I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The wedding&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never trust a golfer</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NB&lt;/strong&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;m actually writing this 3 months after we ran this hill, mostly because life got a
bit busy, we had a holiday in the Alpes, blah blah blah, the usual excuses.  Anyway, here it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What better activity to do on the hottest May Bank Holiday on record, than go for a run?  I
think that this might count as a genuinely stupid thing to do, especially when you know it&amp;rsquo;s
coming.  All of the forecasts predicted scorching temperatures (for Britain), and Julie and I
&lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; planned to go running.  Yeah, not the brightest idea.  We thought we&amp;rsquo;d be really clever,
and try to aim to get out early in the morning before it got too hot.  I believe there is a
phrase about best laid plans or something&amp;hellip;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/bedfordshire_map.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The route&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pulled into a packed car park at the Gateway to the Chilterns, with a plan to set off along
the ridge of the Dunstable Downs.  My route plan had us start along the Icknield Way Trail,
which we would follow on and off for most of the route.  However, there were at least 3
different trail posts indicating the trail, thankfully all in the same direction.  We headed
off obvliviously along the trail, scatter with tree roots, thankful for what little shade we
could get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our navigational error, which led us in a small circle around a wood, was caused by the sudden
appearance of a woodland assault course.  Never one to turn down a challenge we vaulted over
logs and jumped through tyres.  However, clearly we weren&amp;rsquo;t the only ones to make this error as
we approached a farm, two young farmhands waved us back down the road from whence we came, along
with several confused hikers.  Eventually we found ourselves back on roughly the right path and
continued on our merry way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We followed the Chiltern way through Whipsnade village, past all of the cars queueing to get
into the safari park, and down past the zoo.  Unfortunately, we could not see any of the
animals, only some of the local wild deer.  The path took us weaving through various fields, and
wooded plantations scattered with bluebells, though not nearly enough to shade us
from the oppressive sun beating down on us.  Popping on the golf course, we followed
the directions indicated to us by a group of apparently friendly golfers.  Cue navigational
error number 2, as we sped across the fairways, following the way markers past the club house,
and steeply down hill to a road.  This got my spider senses tingling, as I realised that we
weren&amp;rsquo;t due to hit any roads for at least another couple of miles.  Much to our chagrin, we had
to run back up the steep hill we had just barelled down to correct our mistake.  To cut a long
story short, never trust a golfer giving you &amp;ldquo;helpful&amp;rdquo; directions.  We managed to find our way
back onto the correct (and also waymarked) path, over the golf course, dodging golf balls and
bunkers as we went.  Eventually we emerged back on to the path round the back of the zoo, where
we got a great view across to the elephant enclosure, not what one would normally expect in
the middle of rural Bedfordshire!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/blue_bells.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Some bluebells&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We traversed several muddy sections of the path, trying to keep an eye out for any other
misplaced African behemoths, but we were sadly disappointed.  Retracing our footsteps through
Whipsnade we cut left past a curious landmark; a tree cathedral.  We could only guess at the
true purpose of this strange arboreal arrangement, as we climbed back up the Ickneild way onto
the Dunstable Downs, and into the unrelenting bank holiday heat.  The thought of an ice cream
spurred us on along the final exposed ridgeline and back to the visitor centre from where we
started out.  Teeming with families flying kites and enjoying picnics, we gobbled down a couple
of ice creams in double time, thankful for the small piece of shade we could find.  At this
point we still hadn&amp;rsquo;t strictly speaking hit the summit, as this was an indescript square of land
marked only by a countour on the map, possibly somewhere in the carpark.  However, I almost
certainly sure that we had reached the &amp;ldquo;highest point&amp;rdquo; in Bedfordshire, as my GPS said we were
at a dizzying 243 metres, which was in agreement with the map.  Seeing as I was in danger of
breaking multiple rules on this run (my phone didn&amp;rsquo;t track the run properly), we drove down to
Studham, where we had run through earlier, and tucked into a couple of pints of shandy with a
slap up fish supper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/summit_selfie2_bedfordshire.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The &amp;quot;summit&amp;quot;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve signed off all these blog posts so far with how I would change things, or maybe a lesson
that I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt.  Firstly, it&amp;rsquo;s really fun running with Julie, and she keeps me well motivated,
so as long as she want&amp;rsquo;s to keep running these hills then that&amp;rsquo;s great for me!  Neither of us
deals with the heat very well.  It actually turns out that whilst this was the hottest day of
the year until that point, things were going to get much, much hotter.  This heat is a problem
for running, so I think I need to try to pick and choose days with more appropriate weather if
possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/what_a_view.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Not a bad view&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, toodle pips for now; there&amp;rsquo;s a bigger hill coming very, very soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icy Death Wind</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a fun couple of months since my last hill challenge run back at Christmas.  In that time I&amp;rsquo;ve trained for the Cambridge half marathon, it&amp;rsquo;s snowed, Julie and I moved in together (in the snow), and then we both ran the Cambridge half the day after (thankfully not in the snow; but it has snowed again since).  This blog is called &amp;lsquo;Stupid Things&amp;rsquo;; I think running a half marathon the day after moving house, with just the two of us doing all of the lifting, counts as something stupid.  There was a lot of discussion about whether we would even (be able to) run, but we both got round, my slowest, but not Julie&amp;rsquo;s.  Win!  I just managed to squeak in under 2hours (literally by ~20 seconds), so all in all I feel like we pulled it off with style and panache (we didn&amp;rsquo;t look it after, that&amp;rsquo;s for sure).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/half_selfie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;post half marathon selfie&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a couple of weeks, and we found ourselves in Norfolk at Julies&amp;rsquo; brother&amp;rsquo;s wedding (thanks Rich &amp;amp; Nikki!).  It was just north of Norwich, and given the that the Norfolk &amp;lsquo;hill&amp;rsquo; was up on the coast near Cromer, it seemed like an awful waste just to go straight back to Cambridge&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend running a half marathon immediately after moving house, it was considerably worse than running up a &amp;lsquo;hill&amp;rsquo; after a family wedding.  I&amp;rsquo;ve convinced myself that rum and dancing are a really good way to prepare for hill running. Honestly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our monolithic target was Beacon Hill at a spectacular 103m. Whoa!  How could anyone ever run up anything that high?! Killian Jornet eat your heart out.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QGKsFyHNwbs&#34;&gt;Everest in a day?&lt;/a&gt; Pfft, get yourself to Norfolk lad&amp;hellip; #sarcasm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, if ever there was a time to run the second lowest county hill (the lowest is reserved for the City of London - Julie has a great idea for that one), straight after a rum fueled family wedding is arguably the best.  I broke a couple of rules with this run, well, nearly all of them as it turns out.  Firstly, I didn&amp;rsquo;t plan a 10k run, it was only about 5 miles in total, partly that was due to the lay of the land, and partly because I thought I might still be steaming from the night before.  I also didn&amp;rsquo;t have a beer at the end, I definitely had my fair share in the previous 24hours, so I thought that one could slide too.  But don&amp;rsquo;t worry folks, there was still plenty of suffering to be had!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started off next to the summit.  Yes, they actually have a car park at the top, even this hill is too much for your average Norfolk-ian (it&amp;rsquo;s actually because there&amp;rsquo;s an old roman fort there, nothing to do with the dizzying altitude).  It was a bit tricky creating a circular route that wasn&amp;rsquo;t either 2 miles or 10 miles.  I knackered my knee a little doing the Cambridge half as well, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly willing to push the distance too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The route began down hill, and over the main Holt Road, the sun was shining, and the hedges by the road kept the worst of the wind at bay.  We turned West at Aylmerton, largely uneventful except for the fact that there was an arctic wind blowing.  Through us. Knives. Icy knives of pain and death.  Neither Julie nor I were prepared for this level of suffering. I&amp;rsquo;ve stood on top of a Munro in Scotland in a full Scottish winter conditions and felt warmer. We quickly arrived full circle at Holt Road (about 1.5 km further West) and plunged into the much welcome shelter of a woodland. The variety in the route was quite surprsing, as much as the weather.  We definitely felt that, despite the small stature of the hill, we were getting our money&amp;rsquo;s worth so to speak.  Through the Beeston Regis Heath and nature reserve, we followed the base of the hill, and past the Sheringham shire horse sanctuary (say that after a couple of pints).  I have developed a little bit of a reputation for navigational problems on all previous runs to date.  This one was no exception, though paled in comparison to my other efforts.  My plan was to take one of the tracks up the hill which would deposity us right in the middle of the roman camp, and next to a warm car.  Ha! Not a chance.  In my impatience, I made us take a path a hundred meters too early and we just ended up next to some benches.  But it was a pretty good view through a break in the trees out over the North Sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/norfolk_view2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I see, I see, no ships today&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a little bit of dithering, we found the main track to the carpark, and after no more than 200 metres we found the car, and the summit.  Hooray!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/norfolk_selfie1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;We made it to the top of Norfolk!&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the top there was a lovely view out to sea, and a little bit of historical interest with the old roman camp.  I had assumed that this hill would just be an indistinguishable bit of a path, much like &lt;a href=&#34;https://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round2/&#34;&gt;Cambridgeshire&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round1/&#34;&gt;Essex&lt;/a&gt;, but I was pleasantly surprised.  The information board even confirmed that this was (one of) the highest point(s) in Norfolk (though I missed that bit, thanks for pointing it out Julie).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/norfolk_camp2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;some history&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/norfolk_board.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;information - very educational&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In total I think we managed ~5 miles.  Unfortunately the pinnacle of Norfolk knocked out my GPS (it might have been the trees actually), so I didn&amp;rsquo;t get the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.endomondo.com/users/3375171/workouts/1085427324&#34;&gt;full route recorded&lt;/a&gt;.  That&amp;rsquo;s 3 rules I broke, oops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a far more adventurous and eventful run than I had bargained for, and it was great fun to share it with Julie.  Hopefully she&amp;rsquo;ll agree to keep sharing my suffering as the hills get bigger and bigger.  No beer, less than 10km, and not fully recorded.  Who cares though? If it wasn&amp;rsquo;t for the icy death wind, it would have been quite a pleasant experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icy Death Wind</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/content/round5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/content/round5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a fun couple of months since my last hill challenge run back at Christmas.  In that time I&amp;rsquo;ve trained for the Cambridge half marathon, it&amp;rsquo;s snowed, Julie and I moved in together (in the snow), and then we both ran the Cambridge half the day after (thankfully not in the snow; but it has snowed again since).  This blog is called &amp;lsquo;Stupid Things&amp;rsquo;; I think running a half marathon the day after moving house, with just the two of us doing all of the lifting, counts as something stupid.  There was a lot of discussion about whether we would even (be able to) run, but we both got round, my slowest, but not Julie&amp;rsquo;s.  Win!  I just managed to squeak in under 2hours (literally by ~20 seconds), so all in all I feel like we pulled it off with style and panache (we didn&amp;rsquo;t look it after, that&amp;rsquo;s for sure).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/half_selfie.jpg&#34;&gt;post half marathon selfie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a couple of weeks, and we found ourselves in Norfolk at Julies&amp;rsquo; brother&amp;rsquo;s wedding (thanks Rich &amp;amp; Nikki!).  It was just north of Norwich, and given the that the Norfolk &amp;lsquo;hill&amp;rsquo; was up on the coast near Cromer, it seemed like an awful waste just to go straight back to Cambridge&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend running a half marathon immediately after moving house, it was considerably worse than running up a &amp;lsquo;hill&amp;rsquo; after a family wedding.  I&amp;rsquo;ve convinced myself that rum and dancing are a really good way to prepare for hill running. Honestly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our monolithic target was Beacon Hill at a spectacular 103m. Whoa!  How could anyone ever run up anything that high?! Killian Jornet eat your heart out.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QGKsFyHNwbs&#34;&gt;Everest in a day?&lt;/a&gt; Pfft, get yourself to Norfolk lad&amp;hellip; #sarcasm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, if ever there was a time to run the second lowest county hill (the lowest is reserved for the City of London - Julie has a great idea for that one), straight after a rum fueled family wedding is arguably the best.  I broke a couple of rules with this run, well, nearly all of them as it turns out.  Firstly, I didn&amp;rsquo;t plan a 10k run, it was only about 5 miles in total, partly that was due to the lay of the land, and partly because I thought I might still be steaming from the night before.  I also didn&amp;rsquo;t have a beer at the end, I definitely had my fair share in the previous 24hours, so I thought that one could slide too.  But don&amp;rsquo;t worry folks, there was still plenty of suffering to be had!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started off next to the summit.  Yes, they actually have a car park at the top, even this hill is too much for your average Norfolk-ian (it&amp;rsquo;s actually because there&amp;rsquo;s an old roman fort there, nothing to do with the dizzying altitude).  It was a bit tricky creating a circular route that wasn&amp;rsquo;t either 2 miles or 10 miles.  I knackered my knee a little doing the Cambridge half as well, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly willing to push the distance too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The route began down hill, and over the main Holt Road, the sun was shining, and the hedges by the road kept the worst of the wind at bay.  We turned West at Aylmerton, largely uneventful except for the fact that there was an arctic wind blowing.  Through us. Knives. Icy knives of pain and death.  Neither Julie nor I were prepared for this level of suffering. I&amp;rsquo;ve stood on top of a Munro in Scotland in a full Scottish winter conditions and felt warmer. We quickly arrived full circle at Holt Road (about 1.5 km further West) and plunged into the much welcome shelter of a woodland. The variety in the route was quite surprsing, as much as the weather.  We definitely felt that, despite the small stature of the hill, we were getting our money&amp;rsquo;s worth so to speak.  Through the Beeston Regis Heath and nature reserve, we followed the base of the hill, and past the Sheringham shire horse sanctuary (say that after a couple of pints).  I have developed a little bit of a reputation for navigational problems on all previous runs to date.  This one was no exception, though paled in comparison to my other efforts.  My plan was to take one of the tracks up the hill which would deposity us right in the middle of the roman camp, and next to a warm car.  Ha! Not a chance.  In my impatience, I made us take a path a hundred meters too early and we just ended up next to some benches.  But it was a pretty good view through a break in the trees out over the North Sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/norfolk_view2.jpg&#34;&gt;I see, I see, no ships today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a little bit of dithering, we found the main track to the carpark, and after no more than 200 metres we found the car, and the summit.  Hooray!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/norfolk_selfie1.jpg&#34;&gt;We made it to the top of Norfolk!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the top there was a lovely view out to sea, and a little bit of historical interest with the old roman camp.  I had assumed that this hill would just be an indistinguishable bit of a path, much like &lt;a href=&#34;https://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round2/&#34;&gt;Cambridgeshire&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round1/&#34;&gt;Essex&lt;/a&gt;, but I was pleasantly surprised.  The information board even confirmed that this was (one of) the highest point(s) in Norfolk (though I missed that bit, thanks for pointing it out Julie).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/norfolk_camp2.jpg&#34;&gt;some history&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/norfolk_board.jpg&#34;&gt;information - very educational&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In total I think we managed ~5 miles.  Unfortunately the pinnacle of Norfolk knocked out my GPS (it might have been the trees actually), so I didn&amp;rsquo;t get the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.endomondo.com/users/3375171/workouts/1085427324&#34;&gt;full route recorded&lt;/a&gt;.  That&amp;rsquo;s 3 rules I broke, oops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a far more adventurous and eventful run than I had bargained for, and it was great fun to share it with Julie.  Hopefully she&amp;rsquo;ll agree to keep sharing my suffering as the hills get bigger and bigger.  No beer, less than 10km, and not fully recorded.  Who cares though? If it wasn&amp;rsquo;t for the icy death wind, it would have been quite a pleasant experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two for the price of one</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2017 is over, and there&amp;rsquo;s a pretty big dent in January.  I started my running challenge to try to motivate me
back into running generally, hill running specifically, and because I like to tell people I think suffering is
good for the soul.  What better time of year to suffer, than Christmas? (I get on with my family pretty well,
so they aren&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; a source of suffering tbh).  Of course I&amp;rsquo;m talking about going for a windy, sleety
run on Christmas day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mum lives in North Hampshire, and seeing as I was down for the festive period, I thought it would be an
ideal opportunity to tick off not one, but two hills from the list; the two highest to date as well.  Pilot hill (286m)
in Hampshire, and Walbury Hill (297m) in Berkshire both stand on the Wayfarer&amp;rsquo;s Way that cuts across the North
Hampshire downs (it also apparently starts just past &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.britishwalks.org/walks/Named/WayfarersWalk.php&#34;&gt;Walbury Hill at Inkpen Beacon&lt;/a&gt;).  My Mum and I drove out to the carpark
at Coombe Gibbet; she went off to walk Ella, the family dog, whilst I ran.  As we got closer to our
destination it became apparently clear that the weather would not be on my side.  The wind was howling off
of the top of the ridgeway, driving the freezing sleet and rain like icy knives straight through me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My route initially took me off the hill and down into the quaint village of Coombe.  Seeing as we were parked
so close to the summit of one of the hills, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to peak (pun intended) too early.  It also turns
out that running straight down hill for a mile before warming up is almost as much fun as running straight up
one.  You live and learn!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/hants_berks_route1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;the route in all its glory&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Coombe I was to take a cross-country route, up Sugglestone Down to a radio mast before a long slow drop
down in to Faccombe (Faccombe all!).  I am nothing, if not consistent, so I got lost, as I have on nearly
every single one of these runs.  I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s my shocking sense of direction or orientation (Julie
will say it&amp;rsquo;s my lack of orientation no doubt), but sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s hard to find what should be marked
footpaths.  After a very steep slog up Sugglestone Down (I may have walked a little bit&amp;hellip;), I set off across
a field in what I thought was the right general direction; I could even see the radio mast I was aiming for.
Unfortunately it seems that most of the paths cut straight across farmers fields.  Fields that tend to get
ploughed on an annual basis.  Sometimes they plough across the paths and obliterated.  See where this is
going?  Anyway, after running around a cornfield, scaring the bejeesus out of every pheasant and partridge in
Hampshire, and one or two buzzards (so cool!), I found the road I&amp;rsquo;d been looking for.  In my defence, these
little detours are getting shorter each time, I think I probably only added on an extra kilometre, if that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The road down to Faccombe (it is as rude as it sounds), was a good opportunity to settle into a steady pace.
I was particularly mindful that I had agreed to meet my mother back at the car at a specific time, and I was
already behind schedule (thankfully the turkey was in the oven), but we were expecting guests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I keep  banging on, this challenge is about running up hills, so I&amp;rsquo;ve have deliberately planned several
ups and downs into each route, not necessarily just the intended summits.  I&amp;rsquo;d come down the off the
ridgeway, and thrown one hill into the route already, so it was time to get back up onto the ridgeway proper.
Whitehorse hill in Oxford was short, but steep, and the hills in Cambridgeshire and Essex were
fairly unimpressive.  My point is that up until this point I hadn&amp;rsquo;t actually run up many hills.  The long
slog out of Faccombe was a real test, and to be honest, I was found wanting.  The muddy path took a short
dip down to the bottom of the valley, before heading up through woods and along field boundaries before
depositing me on the Wayfarer&amp;rsquo;s Way.  I struggled with this hill, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; struggled.  About three quarters
of the way up I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep it up.  I told myself that I stopped because it looked like there was a
path off to my left I might have to take.  I&amp;rsquo;d looked at the map in Faccombe, so I knew that the only
navigational choice was when the path ran out.  In all honesty, I was absolutely bollocksed.  My fitness was
not up to scratch, and this hill really hit that home.  I can make excuses about there not being any hills
in and around Cambridge to train on, but the truth is I&amp;rsquo;d let my running and training slip in the previous
months.  The fact that this was the first hill run in nearly six months is testament to that fact.  I have
resolved to not let such long lapses happen again, but I don&amp;rsquo;t like to make promises I can&amp;rsquo;t keep!  I&amp;rsquo;ll
just have to be a bit more mindful about keeping the running up.  That&amp;rsquo;s not an issue right now as I&amp;rsquo;m
training for the Cambridge half marathon in March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless I made it on to the Wayfarers way, where I was greeted first by an icy cold slap of wind to the
chops, and secondly by a quagmire.  I had thought that from this point it would be easy sailing, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty
flat all the way, and I still had about two and a half miles to get back to the car (and the awaiting
turkey).  I considered walking, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think it would have made a huge amount of difference.  I slipped
my way along the footpath, past a rather bemused family, and set off across a field in hope of finding a
trig point that marked the summit of Pilot hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/pilot_hill.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;a &amp;quot;view&amp;quot; from pilot hill&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/pilot_selfie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pilot hill selfie&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was at this point that the bemused family&amp;rsquo;s dog started playing a game.  A game that involves it getting
as close to me as it dared, whilst barking, then sprinting away as fast as possible, intentionally in the
opposite direction of it&amp;rsquo;s rather embarassed looking owner.  Having helped entice the dog back to it&amp;rsquo;s owner
I jumped back onto the muddy path (carefully), and carried on slipping, squelching and sliding my way to the
next summit.  Trees, metal barriers, deer, and deep filthy pits of muds were leapt over, siddled past and
ineleganty clambered over (not the deer).  The second summit, another trig point, was smack bang in the middle of another
farmers field.  I figured that on Christmas day the farmer wouldn&amp;rsquo;t begrudge some mad runner jogging to an
arbitrary spot in the middle of their field.  I clambered over the fence, and in my haste totally missed the
ground, sending my foot flying upwards and my bum downwards rather more rapidly than I&amp;rsquo;d bargained for. In
truly suave style I scrabbled to get up by clutching at the metal gate, trying to get some purchase in the
mud.  Probably looking somewhat like Bambi on ice, I found my feet and ran across the field towards the trig
point.  I was running straight into the icy rain now, and my sense of humour was on the verge of failing me.
Until of course I remembered this was exactly what I&amp;rsquo;d come for.  Freezing wind, icy rain, treachorous mud;
perfect!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made it to the trig point, snapped a selfie and one of the glorious &amp;ldquo;view&amp;rdquo; (judge for yourselves), before
running back to the fence.  I sent my mum a quick message to say I was 5 minutes out (it turns out I
actually sent it to the wrong parent and got a bemused phone call from my father), and finished the last
half a mile or so in the driving rain.  No time to stretch out or catch my breath I jumped in the car and
we set off home.  I figured stopping for a pint wasn&amp;rsquo;t necessary, there was
plenty of booze waiting back at home!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/warbury_selfie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;warbury hill selfie&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/warbury_2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;warbury hill, what a view&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve ended all of these posts so far with the lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt, and what I&amp;rsquo;ll change for the next.  I
didn&amp;rsquo;t have any particular take away lessons, aside from lack of fitness.  I&amp;rsquo;ve finished the year with 5
hills in the bag, which to be honest, I had thought I would have completed a few more than that.  At least
it gives me a fairly easy resolution for next year!  I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I can manage 6&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.endomondo.com/users/3375171/workouts/1047455479&#34;&gt;Endomondo route&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Oxford</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well it&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since my last official county hill run, 3 months by my reckoning.  In all honesty that was maybe leaving it a bit too long, but I have to also be honest with myself; this is a long-term challenge.  In those 3 months I have been keeping myself pretty busy, and my time was largely dominated by training and preparation for a week in the Alps.  It was well worth it, and I had an absolutely fantastic time out in Chamonix.  It was my first real proper taste of being in an alpine environment, without being on a skiing trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bonus was that training for a week of climbing in mountaineering turned out be pretty good prep for running up hills in the UK!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/chamonix.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;the mer de glace, with the Grand Jorasses in the left background&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I planned this run waaaay back in Easter, on a short break in the Pyrenees with some friends, and old housemates, from Oxford (that was another great trip).  The only time Sarah and I could make was all the way into July, but I am committed to this challenge so I put it in the diary.  I thought I might have managed a few more hills between now and then, so much for grand plans!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;July 8th came along, and after a few too many beers at the work summer party the evening before, I set off to Oxford.  The hill we were aiming for was White Horse hill, a towering green mound, nestled in the shadow of which lies the sleepy village of Uffington.  We left the car in Fox &amp;amp; Hounds carpark, and set off for a little warm up.  There aren&amp;rsquo;t any other hills around, though White Horse hill itself does lie on the Ridgeway; a spine of hills that stretches some 80+ miles from Ivinghoe Beacon in Hertfordshire, through Oxfordshire, and into Wiltshire where it ends at West Kennett.  I&amp;rsquo;ve long talked about riding the Ridgeway as the vast majority of it is formed of bridleway, but sadly it hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet come to pass.  A couple of years ago a friend (Jody) and I did cycle out from Oxford to the hill, up and along the ridgeway for a few miles, before making our way back to Oxford.  This meant that I had the advantage of knowing what lay in store for me (and Sarah) with this particular hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/whitehorse_map.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;the route map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d planned a little circuitous route so we could warm our legs up a little before hitting the steep section.  A couple of uneventful miles on roads and tracks, and a chance to have a catch up with Sarah was welcome especially on such a scorchingly hot day.  Thankfully we had a bit of breeze to cool things down (though I would have been more thankful if it was 10˚C colder).  As we set off up the hill the chatter died down and we plodded slowly and steadily up the winding path, avoiding the steepest section of hill; you can&amp;rsquo;t actually climb up it reasonably, especially with signs all over the place telling you to stick to the path (for shame&amp;hellip;).  The last section was on broken chalk track, then grass.  My lungs were burning with the effort, the first time I&amp;rsquo;d really done that sort of cardio for quite some time.  We reached the summit, a proper trig marker rather than just a vague area on a map.  My hands on my knees, gulping in lung fulls of air, trying to remember to enjoy myself!  I recovered my breath, snapped a summit selfie with Sarah, and a couple more of the glorious view across the flat Oxfordshire plane, then we were off again to enjoy the rest of the run, the strenuous bit over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/summit_selfie3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;summit selfie!&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/whitehorse_panorama.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;panoramic view from the top&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running slightly downhill along the Ridgeway path felt like freedom after the short, sharp, run to the summit.  We checked the map a couple more times to make sure we had the right path and set off downwards by the edges of fields of golden wheat.  This is where the &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo; (read that as type 2 fun) really began.  I was regalling Sarah with a fascinating (ha!) tale of running through a solid patch of stinging nettles on a recent run up the Cam to Waterbeach to see Julie.  No sooner did we jump over a stile, but lo behold!  A solid wall of nettles, only a vague impression of the path we were supposed to be following.  In these kind of situations I tend to just try and barge my way through and deal with the consequences at the end (that is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; a metaphor).  Sarah, who was out in front, was very much of the gently, gently approach.  This worked to some extent, in that it probably reduced how much we got stung, but in my impatience I kept urging her to just keep running straight through and (wo)man up about it.  In all fairness, there&amp;rsquo;s a time to step gently, and there&amp;rsquo;s a time for action.  So I ran past, and straight in to an even thicker bush of nettles (Sarah&amp;rsquo;s approach was in all fairness probably the best).  We finally reached a gate and a proper break in the little green stinging bastards.  Our legs and arms were covered in blebs, which with the salty sweat, just meant everything felt like we&amp;rsquo;d rubbed ourselves in hot, spicy chilis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We carried on, yet more fun awaited us.  With only a couple of miles to go it seemed that we were on the home straight.  Across a sheep field, then a right hand turn over a couple more field boundaries and plonk, right back in the car park.  Of course, no trail run in the country with Mike would be complete without at least one navigational screw up!  What was supposed to be a very straightforward line across a field to the other side, turned into a jumbled mess of criss-crossing our previous steps as we repeatedly tried, and failed, to find the way out of the sheep field we found ourselves in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/whitehorse_lost.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;getting out of a field is really, really hard&#34; /&gt;
(the astute will notice that Sarah&amp;rsquo;s Strava time up White Horse hill is the fastest women&amp;rsquo;s time)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from scarring the crap out of a load of sheep, all we succeeded in doing was finding out all of the points in two neighbouring fields where you &lt;em&gt;couldn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; get out.  Nearly at wit&amp;rsquo;s end we took one more punt (again consulting the GPS): we were in luck!  After some 30+ minutes of searching we found the path out of the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/the_path.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;salvation at last!&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the same reckless joy as Theresa May, we flew through the fields of wheat (though less U-turns on our part).  Finally on the last stretch back to the car, and the much awaited pint of shandy and nuts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/whitehorse_beer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nuts to that&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall we were out for about an hour and three quarters (8.3 miles in 1:25 of actual running), so it definitely wasn&amp;rsquo;t the fastest so far, but it was eventful.  Whilst running up the hill itself was hard, we could see the top, so it felt feasible, and with some more training would be a lot easier. Saying that, I think my time in the alps the week previous probably didn&amp;rsquo;t hurt my hill fitnesss.  The lesson I learnt, consult the GPS (phone) before spending too much time trying to navigate, or stop faffing and at least try to triangulate my position properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m starting to get the hang of things, and this run has certainly got me motivated to try a few more hills.  I&amp;rsquo;m still a long, long way from running up the big hills (think Scafell Pike, The Cheviot, anything in Scotland), but running 8.3 miles, albeit slowly, without any trouble is a confidence boost.  I really feel like getting back to half marathon fitness is not going to be a particularly arduous task; watch this space for my first trail half maration race in November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ciao for now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>County number 2</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a confession to make.  In my last post I told you that I had run up Great Chishill, that towering edifice of Cambridgeshire.  I lied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hill in nearby Essex is called Chishill Common, and stands at a lofty 147m.  Great Chishill is it&amp;rsquo;s little sister at 146m.  They are both within a few miles of each other, so when I planned the route for my first foray into this project, I went looking for the highest point in that area.  So basically I ran up the right hill, in the wrong county.  Disaster averted, because today I ran up the real Great Chishill (which is still in Cambridgeshire)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can even see on the map (OS Explorer 194) just how close the two hills are.  So close in fact, that the route today overlapped with a section Fred and I ran a fortnight ago (you can just make it out on the right hand side).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/map_route2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;route map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started at another pub (of course), The Pheasent in Great Chishill and proceeded to run in the opposite direction to the hill; there&amp;rsquo;s no way I was getting cheated out of a decent 10km run by Cambridgeshire&amp;rsquo;s paucity of proper hills.  All was going well, there was a bit more road than last time, but these were mostly on quiet country lanes.  As we ran down through Shaftenhoe End Fred and I hit our first navigation decision, so we took what we thought was our preordained path to hilly glory.  Well Abbotsbury House to be accurate.  However, instead of taking the path &lt;em&gt;we thought we were on&lt;/em&gt;, we actually managed to veer off left throwing us off course.  Unfortunately we did not realise our error, and so continued to try to navigate around the farm, looking for a crucial footpath (we&amp;rsquo;d already run down it :-( ).  What transpired was an exercise in futility, shockingly bad orienterring, and about a 3km detour.  The extent of our futility was captured by Endomondo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.endomondo.com/users/3375171/workouts/898122913&#34;&gt;https://www.endomondo.com/users/3375171/workouts/898122913&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suffice to say we ended up heading in completely the opposite direction that we wanted, and much, much closer to the gun shots coming from the nearby estate.  With help of modern technology (thanks Google Maps), we realised our mistake and got back to Abbotsbury House, and our intended path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that it was pretty uneventful, the weather was stunning, and there was very little wind.  The course of the route crosses three county borders; Cambridgeshire, Hertfordshire and Essex, so I feel that we covered some good ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/essex.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;welcome to essex&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only sting in the tail was the last bridelway to the village was rutted by tractors which made it harder going than the rather gentle incline would suggest.  I also don&amp;rsquo;t think tacking on the extra 3km was helping particularly by that point!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole route was definitely hillier than the first, which was partly intentional as the highest point in Cambridgeshire is unassumingly marked by a 30mph repeater sign.  Anyone could miss that this is the point of greatest altitude in all of Cambridgeshire!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/summit_marker.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Great Chishill marker&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And proof that we were there of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/summit_selfie2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;selfie&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This definitely felt like a bigger challenge than the previous route, as there were many more altitude (!) gains and descents.  We rewarded ourselves with a (now) customary drink in the village pub, which felt more deserved as we tallied up 15km in total.  I have to admit to being slightly proud of myself; this is the furthest I&amp;rsquo;ve run since my injury, and is a real confidence boost that I am well on the road to recovery.  Fred and I even discussed turning one of these smaller challenges into a half marathon route, time will tell whether we do that or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always there are lessons to learn.  The first is to read my spreadsheet of hills properly.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think there will be many more opportunities for this sort of stupid mistake.  I am also going to start carrying a compass.  I think we could have avoided the unnecessary navigational errors by just taking a bearing, and realising we were several hundred metres from our intended position.  This will be especially important for the hills (mountains!) that come later that will not be so easy to navigate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that&amp;rsquo;s 2 hills now, and pretty much the only ones within a 30 minute drive of Cambridge. The next highest hills are in Bristol, Mereseyside and Lincolnshire.  I have to start venturing out into the country properly to start making headway with the others, which is also part of my motivation for doing this challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a side note, there are 3 hills &lt;em&gt;smaller&lt;/em&gt; than the 2 I have run so far, and I need to decide how to incorporate them into a run.  I think I can get to the hill in Suffolk and back in day, Norfolk is a bit trickier.  I think I will struggle with motivation for these smaller hills, as they will definitely feel like less of an achievement, individually at least.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round 1</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great Chishill.  It sounds like it should be some towering natural edifice, rather than a scrappy corner of a field next to a small copse of trees.  It was a good start though, and perhaps a good way to revise my expectations a little.  The lack of hills in and around Cambridge, and my distinct lack of fitness, made this a somewhat tougher challenge than I had expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I planned the route out yesterday after picking up a few OS maps from a local outdoor shop (there&amp;rsquo;s only one in Cambridge that actually sells maps, so no points for guessing).  I can&amp;rsquo;t work out how to render or insert a Google map with the route on, so here&amp;rsquo;s a crappy photo of the route drawn out on a map (OS Explorer 194).  The small red cross is the &amp;ldquo;summit&amp;rdquo;, in the loosest possible sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/map_route1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;the route&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to prove it here&amp;rsquo;s a link to my Endomondo page with the route and elevations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.endomondo.com/users/3375171/workouts/889759118&#34;&gt;https://www.endomondo.com/users/3375171/workouts/889759118&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was joined by my housemate Fred, which I was very grateful of by the end, as I was flagging on the last slog back to the car (and the awaiting beer).  I&amp;rsquo;ve already broken one of my rules, which was to bring back a keepsake of some sort; I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any little stones.  I think I might make this a very flexible rule, afterall, I&amp;rsquo;ve got the maps, &amp;ldquo;summit&amp;rdquo; selfie and Endomondo records.  Perhaps for some of the hills that are a little further afield I&amp;rsquo;ll bring back something a bit more special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/summit_selfie1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;selfie&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main points of this blog, is so that I can look back and see what mistakes I&amp;rsquo;ve made, and what progress I&amp;rsquo;ve made in my running.  I really, really enjoyed this first part of the challenge, despite it being a bit harder than I was expecting.  We had a really strong side/head wind for half of the route, which added to the fun.  Not to mention 2 miles in we discovered the crucial footbridge to get us back onto the path was absent.  In it&amp;rsquo;s place was some red plastic bollards and rail fence.  In the spirit of adventure we clambered down the steep embankement and leapt the 4 feet across to the other side.  A little bit of climbing skills came in handy to get up the 5 foot vertical wall on the other side.  We both made it fine, but came away with more than our fair share of scratches and scrapes from all of the brambles.  If that was the start of the route, then we were going to be in for a good little adventure.  Both Fred and I thoroughly enjoyed ourselves, partly for the adventure (and a bit of route-finding faff), but also because it was harder then we expected.  I had focussed so much on getting a route that took in the summit I didn&amp;rsquo;t entirely pay attention to contours for the rest of the route.  As the old adage says, what goes up must come down, and &lt;em&gt;vice versa&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great start to the challenge, and I&amp;rsquo;ve already learnt a few things for the next challenge.  The first is to carry more water and not worry about the extra weight.  I&amp;rsquo;m not running any mountains yet, so I don&amp;rsquo;t really need to worry too much about going lightweight.  I&amp;rsquo;d also bring some food to leave in the car for when we return.  Luckily we had parked in a pub car park, so we grabbed a cheeky half pint and some nuts, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to guarantee that for all of the hills.  Which brings me on to a new rule:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always have a beer at the end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That should keep me motivated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/introduction/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why?!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this might be the third blog I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to write.  My previous attempts in the past suffered due to lack of a proper theme, motivation; well the usual issues that accompany a chronic lack of creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think (hope?) this one might be a bit different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been pondering a little running project for a few months, and I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got off my bum and started to plan it.  My idea is a based on a book, &amp;lsquo;High Points&amp;rsquo;, which chronicles the adventures of a man who decides to walk up all of the highest points in the UK counties.  Having recently moved to Cambridge, with it&amp;rsquo;s distinct lack of anything more than a few storeys high, I was in desperate need of anything that approximated a hill.  The surest bet to find a hill is to leave Cambridgeshire.  So, I thought why not try to run up all of the highest points in the UK counties?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That seems like a sensible idea Mike&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course there are rules, otherwise I wont do it, and that&amp;rsquo;s not really the point of setting myself this challenge.  In the far distance I will have to run Ben Nevis, Snowdon and Scafell Pike, but there are quite a few counties before with considerably smaller hillocks, mounds and bumps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rules that I have set myself are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The running route must encompass at least the highest in a single county, but can include more if they are close together (there are couple that lie close to county borders)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The distance must be at least 10km.  If I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to travel to do this project, I might as well make it worth my while.  Plus, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure some of the bigger hills would fit into less than 10km&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will record the run (Endomondo, here&amp;rsquo;s looking at you)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will bring back a momento from each hill.  I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest, I got a little stuck here, but I think something simple like a small rock should suffice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are the rules, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think they are so restrictive that I will struggle with them (unlike the running).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another reason that I&amp;rsquo;ve set myself this challenge, other than a chronic need to hills and mountains.  In early 2016 I suffered a very stupid injury, through no ones fault by my own.  I had lost my running motivation after completing the Edinburgh marathon 6 months before, and had a brilliant trip to Armenia in the same year.  Work was piling up, as it does in academia (something about learning to say &amp;lsquo;no&amp;rsquo;&amp;hellip;).  I was sat working on my laptop on the couch at home; I had (have) terrible posture, and after a couple of hours crossed my legs and carried on working for a few more hours.  When I stood up I felt something twinge in my back (it turned out to be a slipped disc), and spent the next few days progressively limping more and more.  It finally reached a crescendo late one evening, and my poor housemates had to spend the night nursing me whilst muscles spasms racked my back.  I have honestly never felt pain like it.  After several days immobile with a cocktail of drugs that would take down a small elephant, started to slowly waddle around again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone who has suffered &amp;ldquo;back pain&amp;rdquo;, this is sadly an area that modern medicine has not been great at tackling, opening the doors for all sorts of quackery.  It, unsurprisingly, turns out that being active is one of the best ways to rehabilitate; prevention is also better than cure in this respect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make a long story short, I spent ~9 months without any proper exercise, gained about 3 stone in weight and lost all of my running and climbing fitness.  Fast forward to November 2016, when I moved to Cambridge to take up a new postdoc position.  I told myself the best way to get my fitness back was to start with running, afterall, if I could run without any back problems then I should be able to do everything I used to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing this in March 2017, and I&amp;rsquo;ve lost a stone already, and I&amp;rsquo;ve pushed my distance to 10km.  I&amp;rsquo;m slower than I used to be, but I feel that my recovering is making real strides.  Given that, I thought I would set myself a &lt;strong&gt;big&lt;/strong&gt; challenge to keep the motivation flowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, 103 counties in England, Scotland and Wales, 103 hills ranging from 22m to 1344m above sea level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go running.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>