<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Stupid Things</title>
    <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Stupid Things</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>County number 2</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a confession to make.  In my last post I told you that I had run up Great Chishill, that towering edifice of Cambridgeshire.  I lied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hill in nearby Essex is called Chishill Common, and stands at a lofty 147m.  Great Chishill is it&amp;rsquo;s little sister at 146m.  They are both within a few miles of each other, so when I planned the route for my first foray into this project, I went looking for the highest point in that area.  So basically I ran up the right hill, in the wrong county.  Disaster averted, because today I ran up the real Great Chishill (which is still in Cambridgeshire)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can even see on the map (OS Explorer 194) just how close the two hills are.  So close in fact, that the route today overlapped with a section Fred and I ran a fortnight ago (you can just make it out on the right hand side).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/map_route2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;route map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started at another pub (of course), The Pheasent in Great Chishill and proceeded to run in the opposite direction to the hill; there&amp;rsquo;s no way I was getting cheated out of a decent 10km run by Cambridgeshire&amp;rsquo;s paucity of proper hills.  All was going well, there was a bit more road than last time, but these were mostly on quiet country lanes.  As we ran down through Shaftenhoe End Fred and I hit our first navigation decision, so we took what we thought was our preordained path to hilly glory.  Well Abbotsbury House to be accurate.  However, instead of taking the path &lt;em&gt;we thought we were on&lt;/em&gt;, we actually managed to veer off left throwing us off course.  Unfortunately we did not realise our error, and so continued to try to navigate around the farm, looking for a crucial footpath (we&amp;rsquo;d already run down it :-( ).  What transpired was an exercise in futility, shockingly bad orienterring, and about a 3km detour.  The extent of our futility was captured by Endomondo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.endomondo.com/users/3375171/workouts/898122913&#34;&gt;https://www.endomondo.com/users/3375171/workouts/898122913&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suffice to say we ended up heading in completely the opposite direction that we wanted, and much, much closer to the gun shots coming from the nearby estate.  With help of modern technology (thanks Google Maps), we realised our mistake and got back to Abbotsbury House, and our intended path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that it was pretty uneventful, the weather was stunning, and there was very little wind.  The course of the route crosses three county borders; Cambridgeshire, Hertfordshire and Essex, so I feel that we covered some good ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/essex.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;welcome to essex&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only sting in the tail was the last bridelway to the village was rutted by tractors which made it harder going than the rather gentle incline would suggest.  I also don&amp;rsquo;t think tacking on the extra 3km was helping particularly by that point!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole route was definitely hillier than the first, which was partly intentional as the highest point in Cambridgeshire is unassumingly marked by a 30mph repeater sign.  Anyone could miss that this is the point of greatest altitude in all of Cambridgeshire!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/summit_marker.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Great Chishill marker&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And proof that we were there of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/summit_selfie2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;selfie&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This definitely felt like a bigger challenge than the previous route, as there were many more altitude (!) gains and descents.  We rewarded ourselves with a (now) customary drink in the village pub, which felt more deserved as we tallied up 15km in total.  I have to admit to being slightly proud of myself; this is the furthest I&amp;rsquo;ve run since my injury, and is a real confidence boost that I am well on the road to recovery.  Fred and I even discussed turning one of these smaller challenges into a half marathon route, time will tell whether we do that or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always there are lessons to learn.  The first is to read my spreadsheet of hills properly.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think there will be many more opportunities for this sort of stupid mistake.  I am also going to start carrying a compass.  I think we could have avoided the unnecessary navigational errors by just taking a bearing, and realising we were several hundred metres from our intended position.  This will be especially important for the hills (mountains!) that come later that will not be so easy to navigate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that&amp;rsquo;s 2 hills now, and pretty much the only ones within a 30 minute drive of Cambridge. The next highest hills are in Bristol, Mereseyside and Lincolnshire.  I have to start venturing out into the country properly to start making headway with the others, which is also part of my motivation for doing this challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a side note, there are 3 hills &lt;em&gt;smaller&lt;/em&gt; than the 2 I have run so far, and I need to decide how to incorporate them into a run.  I think I can get to the hill in Suffolk and back in day, Norfolk is a bit trickier.  I think I will struggle with motivation for these smaller hills, as they will definitely feel like less of an achievement, individually at least.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round 1</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/round1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great Chishill.  It sounds like it should be some towering natural edifice, rather than a scrappy corner of a field next to a small copse of trees.  It was a good start though, and perhaps a good way to revise my expectations a little.  The lack of hills in and around Cambridge, and my distinct lack of fitness, made this a somewhat tougher challenge than I had expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I planned the route out yesterday after picking up a few OS maps from a local outdoor shop (there&amp;rsquo;s only one in Cambridge that actually sells maps, so no points for guessing).  I can&amp;rsquo;t work out how to render or insert a Google map with the route on, so here&amp;rsquo;s a crappy photo of the route drawn out on a map (OS Explorer 194).  The small red cross is the &amp;ldquo;summit&amp;rdquo;, in the loosest possible sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/map_route1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;the route&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to prove it here&amp;rsquo;s a link to my Endomondo page with the route and elevations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.endomondo.com/users/3375171/workouts/889759118&#34;&gt;https://www.endomondo.com/users/3375171/workouts/889759118&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was joined by my housemate Fred, which I was very grateful of by the end, as I was flagging on the last slog back to the car (and the awaiting beer).  I&amp;rsquo;ve already broken one of my rules, which was to bring back a keepsake of some sort; I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any little stones.  I think I might make this a very flexible rule, afterall, I&amp;rsquo;ve got the maps, &amp;ldquo;summit&amp;rdquo; selfie and Endomondo records.  Perhaps for some of the hills that are a little further afield I&amp;rsquo;ll bring back something a bit more special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/summit_selfie1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;selfie&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main points of this blog, is so that I can look back and see what mistakes I&amp;rsquo;ve made, and what progress I&amp;rsquo;ve made in my running.  I really, really enjoyed this first part of the challenge, despite it being a bit harder than I was expecting.  We had a really strong side/head wind for half of the route, which added to the fun.  Not to mention 2 miles in we discovered the crucial footbridge to get us back onto the path was absent.  In it&amp;rsquo;s place was some red plastic bollards and rail fence.  In the spirit of adventure we clambered down the steep embankement and leapt the 4 feet across to the other side.  A little bit of climbing skills came in handy to get up the 5 foot vertical wall on the other side.  We both made it fine, but came away with more than our fair share of scratches and scrapes from all of the brambles.  If that was the start of the route, then we were going to be in for a good little adventure.  Both Fred and I thoroughly enjoyed ourselves, partly for the adventure (and a bit of route-finding faff), but also because it was harder then we expected.  I had focussed so much on getting a route that took in the summit I didn&amp;rsquo;t entirely pay attention to contours for the rest of the route.  As the old adage says, what goes up must come down, and &lt;em&gt;vice versa&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great start to the challenge, and I&amp;rsquo;ve already learnt a few things for the next challenge.  The first is to carry more water and not worry about the extra weight.  I&amp;rsquo;m not running any mountains yet, so I don&amp;rsquo;t really need to worry too much about going lightweight.  I&amp;rsquo;d also bring some food to leave in the car for when we return.  Luckily we had parked in a pub car park, so we grabbed a cheeky half pint and some nuts, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to guarantee that for all of the hills.  Which brings me on to a new rule:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always have a beer at the end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That should keep me motivated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/blog/introduction/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why?!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this might be the third blog I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to write.  My previous attempts in the past suffered due to lack of a proper theme, motivation; well the usual issues that accompany a chronic lack of creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think (hope?) this one might be a bit different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been pondering a little running project for a few months, and I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got off my bum and started to plan it.  My idea is a based on a book, &amp;lsquo;High Points&amp;rsquo;, which chronicles the adventures of a man who decides to walk up all of the highest points in the UK counties.  Having recently moved to Cambridge, with it&amp;rsquo;s distinct lack of anything more than a few storeys high, I was in desperate need of anything that approximated a hill.  The surest bet to find a hill is to leave Cambridgeshire.  So, I thought why not try to run up all of the highest points in the UK counties?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That seems like a sensible idea Mike&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course there are rules, otherwise I wont do it, and that&amp;rsquo;s not really the point of setting myself this challenge.  In the far distance I will have to run Ben Nevis, Snowdon and Scafell Pike, but there are quite a few counties before with considerably smaller hillocks, mounds and bumps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rules that I have set myself are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The running route must encompass at least the highest in a single county, but can include more if they are close together (there are couple that lie close to county borders)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The distance must be at least 10km.  If I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to travel to do this project, I might as well make it worth my while.  Plus, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure some of the bigger hills would fit into less than 10km&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will record the run (Endomondo, here&amp;rsquo;s looking at you)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will bring back a momento from each hill.  I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest, I got a little stuck here, but I think something simple like a small rock should suffice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are the rules, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think they are so restrictive that I will struggle with them (unlike the running).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another reason that I&amp;rsquo;ve set myself this challenge, other than a chronic need to hills and mountains.  In early 2016 I suffered a very stupid injury, through no ones fault by my own.  I had lost my running motivation after completing the Edinburgh marathon 6 months before, and had a brilliant trip to Armenia in the same year.  Work was piling up, as it does in academia (something about learning to say &amp;lsquo;no&amp;rsquo;&amp;hellip;).  I was sat working on my laptop on the couch at home; I had (have) terrible posture, and after a couple of hours crossed my legs and carried on working for a few more hours.  When I stood up I felt something twinge in my back (it turned out to be a slipped disc), and spent the next few days progressively limping more and more.  It finally reached a crescendo late one evening, and my poor housemates had to spend the night nursing me whilst muscles spasms racked my back.  I have honestly never felt pain like it.  After several days immobile with a cocktail of drugs that would take down a small elephant, started to slowly waddle around again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone who has suffered &amp;ldquo;back pain&amp;rdquo;, this is sadly an area that modern medicine has not been great at tackling, opening the doors for all sorts of quackery.  It, unsurprisingly, turns out that being active is one of the best ways to rehabilitate; prevention is also better than cure in this respect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make a long story short, I spent ~9 months without any proper exercise, gained about 3 stone in weight and lost all of my running and climbing fitness.  Fast forward to November 2016, when I moved to Cambridge to take up a new postdoc position.  I told myself the best way to get my fitness back was to start with running, afterall, if I could run without any back problems then I should be able to do everything I used to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing this in March 2017, and I&amp;rsquo;ve lost a stone already, and I&amp;rsquo;ve pushed my distance to 10km.  I&amp;rsquo;m slower than I used to be, but I feel that my recovering is making real strides.  Given that, I thought I would set myself a &lt;strong&gt;big&lt;/strong&gt; challenge to keep the motivation flowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, 103 counties in England, Scotland and Wales, 103 hills ranging from 22m to 1344m above sea level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go running.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>