<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Stupid Things</title>
    <link>/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Stupid Things</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>Untitled.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 10:34:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>/blog/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 10:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- BLOGDOWN-HEAD --&gt;
&lt;!-- /BLOGDOWN-HEAD --&gt;

&lt;!-- BLOGDOWN-BODY-BEFORE --&gt;
&lt;!-- /BLOGDOWN-BODY-BEFORE --&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>/blog/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 10:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/introduction/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oh-look-another-blog&#34;&gt;Oh look, another blog!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this might be the third blog I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to write.  My previous attempts in the past suffered due to lack of a proper theme, motivation; well the usual issues that accompany a chronic lack of creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think (hope?) this one might be a bit different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been pondering a little running project for a few months, and I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got off my bum and started to plan it.  My idea is a based on a book, &amp;lsquo;High Points&amp;rsquo;, which chronicles the story of a man who decides to walk up all of the highest points in the UK counties.  Having recently moved to Cambridge, with it&amp;rsquo;s distinct lack of anything more than a few storeys high, I was in desperate need of anything that approximated a hill.  The surest bet to find a hill is to leave Cambridgeshire.  So, I thought why not try to run up all of the highest points in the UK counties?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That seems like a sensible idea Mike&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course there are rules, otherwise I wont do it, and that&amp;rsquo;s not really the point of setting myself this challenge.  In the far distance I will have to run Ben Nevis, Snowdon and Scafell Pike, but there are quite a few counties before with considerably smaller hillocks, mounds and bumps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rules that I have set myself are:
* The running route must encompass at least the highest in a single county, but can include more if they are close together (there are couple that lie close to county borders)
* The distance must be at least 10km.  If I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to travel to do this project, I might as well make it worth my while.  Plus, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure some of the bigger hills would fit into less than 10km&amp;hellip;
* I will record the run (Endomondo, here&amp;rsquo;s looking at you)
* I will bring back a momento from each hill.  I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest, I got a little stuck here, but I think something simple like a small rock should suffice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are the rules, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think they are so restrictive that I will struggle with them (unlike the running).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>