<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guest on Stupid Things</title>
    <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/categories/guest/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guest on Stupid Things</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <atom:link href="http://mikedmorgan.github.io/categories/guest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Rutland - Small but perfectly formed</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round11-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round11-md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Where the heck is Rutland? I hear you ask.  Well, according to some, it is the smallest county in
England, it holds the largest manmade lake (so basically half of it is a lake) and it is home to the
Nurdling World Championships (Nurdling = throwing pennies in a hole), the winners are crowned the
‘best tosser’, no joke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Route map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on these facts alone, this was shaping up to be a very exciting run.  In addition, it was
February (i.e. my birthday) AND spring had started early.  I think this may have been the only sunny
birthday I have ever had. Rather than trying to fit in all that Rutland had to offer during one hill
run we decided to go to this lovely county two weekends in a row (its only an hour from Cambridge!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weekend 1: A very windy (teehee) 23 mile birthday cycle around Rutland Water.  Mike will deny it but
he was clearly slipstreaming behind me most of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_bike1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland bday biking&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_bike2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland bday biking&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_bike3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland bday biking&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weekend 2: A sunny run to the top of the highest point: Cold Overton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that Rutland has lots of very pretty villages with quaint pubs and old churches, one of
which, Braunston, was the start point of the run.  Braunston is also the site of some historical
stone carvings which are located outside the Church.  If you are running through said churchyard (as
we stared off doing), don’t be too disheartened if you miss them.  If you like I can knock a few
chunks out of a rock, pretty much the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, to the run.  It was sooooo lovely, the daffodils were out and the sun was shining.  The route
took us past the church, and out into some open fields (luckily there was some cover for a nature
wee).  The track wound through Bushy Wood and Haycock Spinney often in directions we were a bit
surprised about based on the map, and out onto a wide farm track (excellent public footpath sign
posting Rutland - not even Mike could get lost).  We popped out onto a small road for a few hundred
meters which then lead onto a footpath where the ascent started up to a lovely viewpoint of the
rolling hills adjacent to a farm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_jump.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland jumping&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_view.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland views&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In classic Mike style we then ran down to the bottom of the hill, and back up a farm track, only to
find that we could just have continued straight on from the viewpoint to arrive in the exact same
place &amp;hellip; .nice one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few more lovely fields later and we had a great view of the highest point we were aiming for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_notHappy.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland happy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We crossed a road and found the track which lead straight up to our destination (yes, straight up).
The trees had recently been cleared and so we found ourselves dancing around trying to dodge roots,
sharp sticks of death and tripping stumps.  Finally the track joined a path across some farmland and
in a few hundred meters we saw the trig point in the middle of a field to the west.  VICTORY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/summit_selfie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland selfie&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_trig1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland trig Julie&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_trig2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland trig Mike&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After retracing our steps to the track we descended a short way before finding the footpath to the east which took us directly back to the village, the car, a pint and a charcuterie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We never thought that the February run would end sitting in a beer garden in the sun but hey, that’s Rutland for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_drink3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland drinks&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/rutland_drink2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rutland drinking&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>