<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tourists on Stupid Things</title>
    <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/categories/tourists/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tourists on Stupid Things</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <atom:link href="http://mikedmorgan.github.io/categories/tourists/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun London</title>
      <link>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mikedmorgan.github.io/post/round13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time. That’s a terrible beginning for any story. But that’s the beginning of
this story. A story of sights, sounds, and gingers. Let’s begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A wise man said that only a ginger may call another ginger “ginger”. He also said
“cheese”, a lot, and had a penchant for lunging. This wise man’s name is Tim. Tim is an
entertainer from a strange country called Oz. We went to see Tim in his “show” before we
decided to run around our nation’s capital. It was funny. Very funny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This running challenge is about running to the highest point in each county. That means
that there is also a lowest point in all these hills. Our low point was London. Don’t get
me wrong, this wasn’t an emotional low point (that crown goes to Suffolk), but physically
the lowest county top is in London. As hinted to above, we went to see Tim Minchin the
night before our run, the plan was to then start at the end of Kensington Gardens and run
through (most) of the royal parks, then along the river, taking in the delights
(read: crowds) at Covent Garden before making the long arduous ascent to….22 meters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan started well - we dropped our bags near Blackfriars, but it turns out London had
a little surprise for us, in the guise of the lord mayor’s show. What is that I hear you
ask? Exactly. We’ve seen it and we aren’t any the wiser. Catching the central line to
Queensway we made our way to the edge of Kensington garden, trying not to make eye
contact with the local wildlife lest they think we were breakfast (REALLY BIG RATS;
gross).  We started, true to all form, by going in the wrong direction. Thankfully, an
overly-familiar Londoner tried to befriend us (I think he must have been new to London),
so we made our excuses and got back on course, running past the round pond and into Hyde
park along the Serpentine, making sure to spend a penny on the way. Duck! Ha ha ha, there
were ducks. And Herons. And seagulls, and stuff like that scattered in amongst the crowds
enjoying a lovely stroll in the park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/heron.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Heron&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, until two sweaty fools came barrelling through them, scaring pigeons left, right
and centre. We cut across the corner from the end of the
Serpentine to Rotten row, leaving the parks and heading across Wellington place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/wellington.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Wellington place&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out the other side we emerged next to Buckingham palace, giving Lizzy a wave, around Canada gate and into St James’ park. Dodging, pigeons and tourists; a blight on this earth, we ran
over the bridge and emerged on to the corner of Parliament square. This is where the fun
began. By fun, I mean semi-jogging passively aggressively behind oblivious tourists
running whenever a gap opened up. We joined the river Thames at Westminster bridge
passing the vacationers gawping at the fake façade covering Big Ben - yet still taking
photos! Strange people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/london_best_photo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Best photo ever&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking the clear path up the river, we ran past Embankment to Waterloo bridge, diverting
up to the theatre district by the Lyceum. We headed up Drury lane (no sign of the muffin
man though. The muffin man? Yes, the muffin man who lives on Drury lane).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/park_selfie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Park selfie&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We emerged on
to High Holborn road, almost the highest point, and trotted over to a derelict church with
a Greco front, next to the museum of comedy (ha!). We snapped our obligatory “summit”
selfie, and backtracked to the river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/comedy_selfie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Summit selfie&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that London had anticipated our run and had kindly closed all the roads
from Waterloo bridge all the way to Blackfriars bridge. How nice (nothing to do with the
“Lord Mayor’s show”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/gog_magog.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Gog and Magog&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Julie made me mention this “best” bit) Just as we were getting back to the station after
collecting our bags we encountered “brass band Bon Jovi” - a brass band playing Jon Bon
Jovi’s classic hit ‘Bad Medicine’. Certainly an experience I’ll never forget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all not a bad run - certainly better than expected given it was a Saturday
afternoon in London. Weather was a bit crap, but it was also in November, so can’t
complain. It was fun, we saw lots of different landmarks, including the Great Albert
Hall, Kensington Palace, Buckingham Palace, Big Ben, Houses of Parliament, Nelson’s
column, Covent Garden and St Paul’s cathedral. Call us tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NB&lt;/strong&gt;: My GPS device was miscalibrated so put our elevation at ~100 metres - this was
definitely not the case! The height of Holborn Hill is a dizzying 22metres, so here&amp;rsquo;s the
OS map we used with our route drawn out in faint pencil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://MikeDMorgan.github.io/img/london_map.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Route map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>